[
  {
    "id": 1501,
    "question": "gracia",
    "questionDetails": "El sacerdote dijo que la gracia divina vela por los niños pequeños.",
    "answer": "grace, mercy",
    "answerDetails": "The priest said that divine grace watches over little children."
  },
  {
    "id": 1502,
    "question": "ruido",
    "questionDetails": "Hacer un ruido.",
    "answer": "noise, sound",
    "answerDetails": "To make a noise."
  },
  {
    "id": 1503,
    "question": "pasada",
    "questionDetails": "El avión hizo 4 pasadas sobre la ciudad y luego se fue a aterrizar.",
    "answer": "pass",
    "answerDetails": "The plane made four passes over the city and then headed back to land."
  },
  {
    "id": 1504,
    "question": "cortar",
    "questionDetails": "Los niños usaron tijeras para cortar el papel en formas diferentes.",
    "answer": "cut, sever",
    "answerDetails": "The children used scissors to cut the paper into different shapes."
  },
  {
    "id": 1505,
    "question": "cabo",
    "questionDetails": "Si subes al faro que está en la punta del cabo, tendrás una vista impresionante del océano.",
    "answer": "cape, corporal",
    "answerDetails": "If you go up the lighthouse located on the tip of the cape, you’ll get a breathtaking view of the ocean."
  },
  {
    "id": 1506,
    "question": "armas",
    "questionDetails": "Lo acusaron de haber vendido armas a Siria.",
    "answer": "arms, military",
    "answerDetails": "He was accused of selling arms to Syria."
  },
  {
    "id": 1507,
    "question": "meta",
    "questionDetails": "¿Cuál es tu meta principal este semestre?",
    "answer": "goal, target",
    "answerDetails": "What’s your main goal this semester?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1508,
    "question": "aprovechar",
    "questionDetails": "Cómo preparar un caballo y aprovecharlo.",
    "answer": "harness, tap, exploit",
    "answerDetails": "How to groom a horse and harness it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1509,
    "question": "rara",
    "questionDetails": "Esta es una obra de una rara delicadeza emocional.",
    "answer": "rare, weird, odd",
    "answerDetails": "This is a work of rare emotional delicacy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1510,
    "question": "prisa",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo prisa por llegar al aeropuerto, ¡ mi avión sale en media hora!.",
    "answer": "rush",
    "answerDetails": "I’m in a rush to get to the airport; my flight leaves in half an hour!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1511,
    "question": "causa",
    "questionDetails": "Dedicó toda su vida adulta a la causa de las personas sordas.",
    "answer": "cause",
    "answerDetails": "She devoted her whole adult life to the cause of deaf people."
  },
  {
    "id": 1512,
    "question": "playa",
    "questionDetails": "Balón or pelota de playa.",
    "answer": "beach, seaside",
    "answerDetails": "Beach ball."
  },
  {
    "id": 1513,
    "question": "contando",
    "questionDetails": "Estaba contando con esto.",
    "answer": "counting, telling, recounting",
    "answerDetails": "I was counting on this."
  },
  {
    "id": 1514,
    "question": "extraña",
    "questionDetails": "Tiene una mirada extraña.",
    "answer": "stranger",
    "answerDetails": "It makes a stranger stare."
  },
  {
    "id": 1515,
    "question": "perdone",
    "questionDetails": "Perdone, no oí lo que dijo.",
    "answer": "excuse me",
    "answerDetails": "Excuse me; I didn’t hear what you said."
  },
  {
    "id": 1516,
    "question": "escuchado",
    "questionDetails": "Seguro has escuchado de alguna estafa.",
    "answer": "heard, listened, overheard",
    "answerDetails": "Surely you’ve heard of a confidence trick."
  },
  {
    "id": 1517,
    "question": "traído",
    "questionDetails": "Éste es el cuarto barco que ha traído.",
    "answer": "brought",
    "answerDetails": "This is the fourth ship he’s brought through."
  },
  {
    "id": 1518,
    "question": "dejarlo",
    "questionDetails": "¿Dónde quieres que estacione el coche?-Puedes dejarlo en la entrada.",
    "answer": "leave it, let it go",
    "answerDetails": "Where do you want me to park the car?-You can leave it in the driveway."
  },
  {
    "id": 1519,
    "question": "piel",
    "questionDetails": "Los Orioles podrían estar dándonos la piel hasta la medianoche.",
    "answer": "skin, fur",
    "answerDetails": "The Orioles might be giving each other skin until midnight."
  },
  {
    "id": 1520,
    "question": "recordar",
    "questionDetails": "Recordar haber hecho algo.",
    "answer": "recall",
    "answerDetails": "To recall doing something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1521,
    "question": "mirada",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca olvidaré su mirada de terror cuando llegó a mi casa.",
    "answer": "look, gaze, eyes",
    "answerDetails": "I’ll never forget her look of terror when she came to my house."
  },
  {
    "id": 1522,
    "question": "corta",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo una lista corta en este lado.",
    "answer": "short, cut, cut off",
    "answerDetails": "Just a short list on that side."
  },
  {
    "id": 1523,
    "question": "compañía",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando el director general sufrió un infarto, le pidieron a nuestro gerente que encabezara la compañía.",
    "answer": "corporation, troupe",
    "answerDetails": "When the CEO suffered a heart attack, our manager was asked to head the corporation."
  },
  {
    "id": 1524,
    "question": "inmediatamente",
    "questionDetails": "La herida no era inmediatamente fatal.",
    "answer": "immediately",
    "answerDetails": "The wound was not immediately fatal."
  },
  {
    "id": 1525,
    "question": "metas",
    "questionDetails": "También usamos la agresión para alcanzar metas.",
    "answer": "goals, targets, aims",
    "answerDetails": "Aggression is also what we use to reach our goals."
  },
  {
    "id": 1526,
    "question": "departamento",
    "questionDetails": "Él era un poco escaso en el Departamento de altura.",
    "answer": "department",
    "answerDetails": "He was a bit lacking in the height department."
  },
  {
    "id": 1527,
    "question": "últimamente",
    "questionDetails": "Últimamente sale del trabajo muy pronto.",
    "answer": "lately",
    "answerDetails": "He’s coming out of work very early lately."
  },
  {
    "id": 1528,
    "question": "cuáles",
    "questionDetails": "El sabía cuáles podrían ser las implicaciones para nosotros.",
    "answer": "what",
    "answerDetails": "He knew what the implications might be for us."
  },
  {
    "id": 1529,
    "question": "caliente",
    "questionDetails": "Él encontró mi historia simplemente demasiado caliente para manejar.",
    "answer": "hot, warm",
    "answerDetails": "He found my story simply too hot to handle."
  },
  {
    "id": 1530,
    "question": "esperamos",
    "questionDetails": "Los esperamos este sábado 23 de febrero a las 12:00 PM para la inauguración de la tienda.",
    "answer": "see you",
    "answerDetails": "See you this Saturday, February 23rd at 12:00 PM for the store’s opening."
  },
  {
    "id": 1531,
    "question": "dedo",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo los pies tan fríos que ya no siento los dedos.",
    "answer": "toe",
    "answerDetails": "My feet are so cold that I can’t feel my toes."
  },
  {
    "id": 1532,
    "question": "tuvieron",
    "questionDetails": "Hasta que tuvieron que llevarlo de urgencia al hospital.",
    "answer": "had",
    "answerDetails": "Until he had to be rushed to the hospital."
  },
  {
    "id": 1533,
    "question": "queríamos",
    "questionDetails": "Queríamos visitarte, pero no tuvimos tiempo.",
    "answer": "we wanted to",
    "answerDetails": "We wanted to visit you, but we didn’t have time."
  },
  {
    "id": 1534,
    "question": "formas",
    "questionDetails": "Sucede a través de distintas formas.",
    "answer": "forms, shapes, ways",
    "answerDetails": "It happens through many different forms."
  },
  {
    "id": 1535,
    "question": "marcha",
    "questionDetails": "Es una marcha de 2 días de aquí a la siguiente ciudad.",
    "answer": "march, going, running",
    "answerDetails": "It is a Two-day March from here to the next city."
  },
  {
    "id": 1536,
    "question": "pocos",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo hay una ceniza roja pocos ahora.",
    "answer": "few",
    "answerDetails": "There are only a few red ashes now."
  },
  {
    "id": 1537,
    "question": "volvemos",
    "questionDetails": "Volvemos a tu casa.",
    "answer": "back",
    "answerDetails": "Back to your place!"
  },
  {
    "id": 1538,
    "question": "vivía",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando vivía junto al mar, iba a la playa por la noche a mirar las estrellas.",
    "answer": "i lived",
    "answerDetails": "When I lived by the sea, I would go to the beach at night to watch the stars."
  },
  {
    "id": 1539,
    "question": "os",
    "questionDetails": "Si os doy esto y unas cuantas monedas.",
    "answer": "you",
    "answerDetails": "And you have some of his coins."
  },
  {
    "id": 1540,
    "question": "papi",
    "questionDetails": "Papi hubiera querido que tengas este dinero.",
    "answer": "pappy",
    "answerDetails": "Pappy would have wanted you to have this money."
  },
  {
    "id": 1541,
    "question": "bienvenida",
    "questionDetails": "Fue a reunirse con ellos con la mano estirada en la bienvenida.",
    "answer": "welcome",
    "answerDetails": "He went to meet them with his hand stretched out in welcome."
  },
  {
    "id": 1542,
    "question": "contenta",
    "questionDetails": "Estoy tan contenta de que se haya ido.",
    "answer": "glad, happy, pleased",
    "answerDetails": "I am so glad she’s gone."
  },
  {
    "id": 1543,
    "question": "encantaría",
    "questionDetails": "A tu madre le encantaría.",
    "answer": "love",
    "answerDetails": "Your mother would love that."
  },
  {
    "id": 1544,
    "question": "clientes",
    "questionDetails": "Habla con los clientes.",
    "answer": "customers, clients, guests",
    "answerDetails": "You talk to the customers."
  },
  {
    "id": 1545,
    "question": "proceso",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitamos un nuevo proceso para escoger un líder de equipo.",
    "answer": "process",
    "answerDetails": "We need a new process for choosing a team leader."
  },
  {
    "id": 1546,
    "question": "escuchaste",
    "answer": "Heard"
  },
  {
    "id": 1547,
    "question": "conversación",
    "questionDetails": "Tuvimos una conversación sobre mi futuro.",
    "answer": "talk, conversation",
    "answerDetails": "We had a talk about my future."
  },
  {
    "id": 1548,
    "question": "firma",
    "questionDetails": "La firma de un directivo Senior.",
    "answer": "signature, firm, signing",
    "answerDetails": "The signature of a senior manager."
  },
  {
    "id": 1549,
    "question": "puedan",
    "questionDetails": "Quizá puedan volver a encontrarse.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "Perhaps we can bring them together."
  },
  {
    "id": 1550,
    "question": "olvida",
    "questionDetails": "Vamos, olvida las llaves.",
    "answer": "forget",
    "answerDetails": "Come on, forget the keys."
  },
  {
    "id": 1551,
    "question": "teniendo",
    "questionDetails": "Teniendo paciencia les damos espacio a los niños para que crezcan.",
    "answer": "by having",
    "answerDetails": "By having patience, we allow our children room to grow."
  },
  {
    "id": 1552,
    "question": "pusieron",
    "questionDetails": "Que ellos pusieron allí.",
    "answer": "put, laid",
    "answerDetails": "Which they put there."
  },
  {
    "id": 1553,
    "question": "piensan",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo piensan en comer.",
    "answer": "think",
    "answerDetails": "You only think of food!"
  },
  {
    "id": 1554,
    "question": "verdadero",
    "questionDetails": "Steer 085 grados verdaderos.",
    "answer": "true, real",
    "answerDetails": "Steer 085 degrees true."
  },
  {
    "id": 1555,
    "question": "próximo",
    "questionDetails": "Edward está entusiasmado por el próximo festivo, porque va a ir a Bali.",
    "answer": "approaching",
    "answerDetails": "Edward is excited about the approaching holiday, because he’s going to go to Bali."
  },
  {
    "id": 1556,
    "question": "lugares",
    "questionDetails": "También tenían lugares maravillosos para almacenar sus granos.",
    "answer": "places, locations, venues",
    "answerDetails": "They also had wonderful places for storing their grain."
  },
  {
    "id": 1557,
    "question": "llevado",
    "questionDetails": "Te pude haber llevado.",
    "answer": "carried, taken, born",
    "answerDetails": "I could have carried you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1558,
    "question": "durmiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que está arriba, durmiendo.",
    "answer": "sleeping, asleep, sleepin’",
    "answerDetails": "I think she’s upstairs sleeping."
  },
  {
    "id": 1559,
    "question": "podrían",
    "questionDetails": "¿Podrían callarse, por favor?",
    "answer": "could you",
    "answerDetails": "Could you quiet down, please?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1560,
    "question": "podías",
    "questionDetails": "Sabía que podías hacerlo.",
    "answer": "could",
    "answerDetails": "I knew we could do it!"
  },
  {
    "id": 1561,
    "question": "abierto",
    "questionDetails": "Estar abierto (a).",
    "answer": "open",
    "answerDetails": "To be open."
  },
  {
    "id": 1562,
    "question": "mayoría",
    "questionDetails": "Hay muchas cosas en el sótano. La mayoría es chatarra.",
    "answer": "most of it, most of them, majority",
    "answerDetails": "There’s a lot of stuff in the basement. Most of it is junk."
  },
  {
    "id": 1563,
    "question": "aquella",
    "questionDetails": "Encuentra la casa de campaña por aquella dirección.",
    "answer": "that",
    "answerDetails": "Find that pump house over that direction."
  },
  {
    "id": 1564,
    "question": "onda",
    "questionDetails": "Alex tiró una piedra al agua, haciendo que aparecieran ondas en la superficie.",
    "answer": "ripple",
    "answerDetails": "Alex threw a stone into the water, making ripples across the surface."
  },
  {
    "id": 1565,
    "question": "justicia",
    "questionDetails": "Hasta que no encontremos a los asesinos, no habrá justicia.",
    "answer": "justice, fairness",
    "answerDetails": "Until we find the killers, there will be no justice."
  },
  {
    "id": 1566,
    "question": "juez",
    "questionDetails": "Dar intervención al juez.",
    "answer": "judge",
    "answerDetails": "The judge will intervene."
  },
  {
    "id": 1567,
    "question": "prensa",
    "questionDetails": "Entrar en prensa.",
    "answer": "press, newspapers",
    "answerDetails": "To go to press."
  },
  {
    "id": 1568,
    "question": "espérame",
    "questionDetails": "Siéntate aquí y espérame.",
    "answer": "wait",
    "answerDetails": "You just sit here and wait."
  },
  {
    "id": 1569,
    "question": "olvidó",
    "questionDetails": "Y alguien olvidó enviarla.",
    "answer": "forgot",
    "answerDetails": "And somebody forgot to mail it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1570,
    "question": "correcto",
    "questionDetails": "Y no lo pensé más, correcto, pero mamá dijo que debería llevarlo a un médico.",
    "answer": "right",
    "answerDetails": "And I didn’t think any more of it, right, but Mum said I should take him to a doctor."
  },
  {
    "id": 1571,
    "question": "encontraron",
    "questionDetails": "Un par de trabajadores de una granja lo encontraron.",
    "answer": "found, encountered",
    "answerDetails": "A couple of farm workers found him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1572,
    "question": "televisión",
    "questionDetails": "Porque no nos has puesto en televisión.",
    "answer": "television",
    "answerDetails": "Because you haven’t put us on television."
  },
  {
    "id": 1573,
    "question": "hiciera",
    "questionDetails": "Me dijeron que lo hiciera.",
    "answer": "do",
    "answerDetails": "They told me to do that."
  },
  {
    "id": 1574,
    "question": "ideas",
    "questionDetails": "Los 2 candidatos tienen ideas muy distintas acerca de cómo abordar la crisis económica.",
    "answer": "thinking",
    "answerDetails": "The two candidates have very different thinking about how to approach the economic crisis."
  },
  {
    "id": 1575,
    "question": "caro",
    "questionDetails": "Mantener un caballo es caro.",
    "answer": "expensive, pricey",
    "answerDetails": "Keeping a horse is expensive."
  },
  {
    "id": 1576,
    "question": "busco",
    "answer": "Seek"
  },
  {
    "id": 1577,
    "question": "valiente",
    "questionDetails": "Era un tiempo para recordar a los valientes.",
    "answer": "brave, valiant, fearless",
    "answerDetails": "It was a time to remember the brave."
  },
  {
    "id": 1578,
    "question": "movimiento",
    "questionDetails": "El movimiento hacia una mayor igualdad sexual.",
    "answer": "movement, motion",
    "answerDetails": "The movement towards greater sexual equality."
  },
  {
    "id": 1579,
    "question": "principal",
    "questionDetails": "Mi trabajo es la razón principal por la que vivo en esta ciudad.",
    "answer": "main, primary, leading",
    "answerDetails": "My job is the main reason why I live in this city."
  },
  {
    "id": 1580,
    "question": "tendrás",
    "questionDetails": "Piensas que si se ve comprometido, no tendrás nada.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "You think if that’s compromised, you have nothing."
  },
  {
    "id": 1581,
    "question": "desastre",
    "questionDetails": "Ella reemplazó a la jarra y se fregado hasta el desastre.",
    "answer": "mess",
    "answerDetails": "She replaced the jug and mopped up the mess."
  },
  {
    "id": 1582,
    "question": "pasaron",
    "questionDetails": "Mara y Luis lo pasaron muy mal el fin de semana pasado porque su bebé se enfermó.",
    "answer": "had, they passed him",
    "answerDetails": "Mara and Luis had a terrible time last weekend because their baby got sick."
  },
  {
    "id": 1583,
    "question": "verde",
    "questionDetails": "Un Putt de 60 pies en el último verde.",
    "answer": "green, blue",
    "answerDetails": "A 60 ft putt on the last green."
  },
  {
    "id": 1584,
    "question": "haberte",
    "questionDetails": "Podrías haberte caído al agua.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "You could have fallen in the water."
  },
  {
    "id": 1585,
    "question": "esquina",
    "questionDetails": "Haz clic en la flecha en la esquina inferior derecha de la página.",
    "answer": "corner",
    "answerDetails": "Click on the arrow in the bottom right corner of the page."
  },
  {
    "id": 1586,
    "question": "humano",
    "questionDetails": "Qué humano de su parte.",
    "answer": "human",
    "answerDetails": "How human of him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1587,
    "question": "base",
    "questionDetails": "Esta idea es la base de toda la economía moderna.",
    "answer": "foundation, basic",
    "answerDetails": "This idea is the foundation of all modern economics."
  },
  {
    "id": 1588,
    "question": "metros",
    "questionDetails": "Se reporta el consumo de agua en metros cúbicos.",
    "answer": "meters, metres, yards",
    "answerDetails": "Total water use is reported in cubic meters."
  },
  {
    "id": 1589,
    "question": "escrito",
    "questionDetails": "Examen escrito.",
    "answer": "written",
    "answerDetails": "Written examination."
  },
  {
    "id": 1590,
    "question": "solas",
    "questionDetails": "Déjeme a solas con él.",
    "answer": "alone, solo, single",
    "answerDetails": "Leave me alone with him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1591,
    "question": "lástima",
    "questionDetails": "Es una lástima que no podamos ir.",
    "answer": "pity, shame",
    "answerDetails": "It’s a pity that we won’t be able to go."
  },
  {
    "id": 1592,
    "question": "resolver",
    "questionDetails": "No desea resolver una línea melódica en el sexto intervalo menor.",
    "answer": "resolve",
    "answerDetails": "You would not want to resolve a melodic line on to the minor 6th interval."
  },
  {
    "id": 1593,
    "question": "mato",
    "questionDetails": "Esta en las noticias, mato a otros.",
    "answer": "kill",
    "answerDetails": "This in the news, kill others."
  },
  {
    "id": 1594,
    "question": "llevaron",
    "questionDetails": "Lo llevaron a la prisión inmediatamente después del juicio.",
    "answer": "he was taken",
    "answerDetails": "He was taken to prison immediately after the trial."
  },
  {
    "id": 1595,
    "question": "taxi",
    "questionDetails": "Taxista mf.",
    "answer": "cab",
    "answerDetails": "Cab driver."
  },
  {
    "id": 1596,
    "question": "vayamos",
    "questionDetails": "Yo digo que vayamos.",
    "answer": "go",
    "answerDetails": "I say we go."
  },
  {
    "id": 1597,
    "question": "casualidad",
    "questionDetails": "“Ud. debe venir a la cafetería con nosotros.” “La casualidad sería una buena cosa.”.",
    "answer": "chance, coincidence, accident",
    "answerDetails": "‘You should come to the cafe with us.’ ‘Chance would be a fine thing.’."
  },
  {
    "id": 1598,
    "question": "sabido",
    "questionDetails": "Es sabido que ese bar deja entrar los menores de edad.",
    "answer": "common knowledge",
    "answerDetails": "It´s common knowledge that that bar lets in minors."
  },
  {
    "id": 1599,
    "question": "recoger",
    "questionDetails": "¿Quién va a recoger los niños de la escuela?",
    "answer": "collect, pick, take up",
    "answerDetails": "Who’s going to collect the kids from school?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1600,
    "question": "acabas",
    "questionDetails": "Me dijeron que acabas de irte.",
    "answer": "just",
    "answerDetails": "They said you just left."
  },
  {
    "id": 1601,
    "question": "abrazo",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que lo que necesitas es un abrazo.",
    "answer": "hug, embrace",
    "answerDetails": "I think what you need is a hug."
  },
  {
    "id": 1602,
    "question": "vacaciones",
    "questionDetails": "¿Qué hiciste durante tus vacaciones de verano?",
    "answer": "holiday, vacation",
    "answerDetails": "What did you do during your summer holidays?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1603,
    "question": "presión",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre me sentí bajo presión en esa empresa.",
    "answer": "pressure",
    "answerDetails": "I always felt under pressure at that company."
  },
  {
    "id": 1604,
    "question": "tele",
    "answer": "TV"
  },
  {
    "id": 1605,
    "question": "usa",
    "questionDetails": "Éste es mi figura de acción favorita. Usa rayos láser para derrotar a sus enemigos.",
    "answer": "it uses, she wears, she uses",
    "answerDetails": "This is my favorite action figure. It uses laser beams to defeat its enemies."
  },
  {
    "id": 1606,
    "question": "vos",
    "questionDetails": "Vos sois muy prudente al desconfiar de estos hombres, señor mío.",
    "answer": "thou",
    "answerDetails": "Thou art most wise to be suspicious of these men, m’lord."
  },
  {
    "id": 1607,
    "question": "regreso",
    "questionDetails": "Tras mi regreso a Nueva York, volví a trabajar de periodista.",
    "answer": "return, comeback",
    "answerDetails": "Following my return to New York, I started working as a journalist again."
  },
  {
    "id": 1608,
    "question": "tocó",
    "questionDetails": "Podemos probar a Charlotte. Tocó el bajo en una banda de Jazz.",
    "answer": "she played, he felt",
    "answerDetails": "We can audition Charlotte. She played bass in a jazz band."
  },
  {
    "id": 1609,
    "question": "aseguro",
    "questionDetails": "Le aseguro que mis intenciones son nobles.",
    "answer": "assure, swear",
    "answerDetails": "I assure you my intentions are honorable."
  },
  {
    "id": 1610,
    "question": "novios",
    "questionDetails": "Sus novios son la misma persona.",
    "answer": "boyfriends, grooms, sweethearts",
    "answerDetails": "Your boyfriends are the same person."
  },
  {
    "id": 1611,
    "question": "confía",
    "questionDetails": "Confía en él y lo necesita.",
    "answer": "relies, trust, entrusted",
    "answerDetails": "He relies on him and he needs him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1612,
    "question": "cansada",
    "questionDetails": "Estoy cansada de mentir.",
    "answer": "tired, weary, sick",
    "answerDetails": "I was tired of lying."
  },
  {
    "id": 1613,
    "question": "detalles",
    "questionDetails": "Haz clic en el siguiente enlace para obtener más detalles sobre el programa del Congreso.",
    "answer": "specifics",
    "answerDetails": "Click on the following link to learn more about the specifics of the conference program."
  },
  {
    "id": 1614,
    "question": "actitud",
    "questionDetails": "No me gusta tu actitud.",
    "answer": "attitude",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t like your attitude."
  },
  {
    "id": 1615,
    "question": "río",
    "questionDetails": "Un río de sangre.",
    "answer": "river",
    "answerDetails": "A river of blood."
  },
  {
    "id": 1616,
    "question": "tonta",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Solo estaba bromeando, tonta!.",
    "answer": "silly, fool",
    "answerDetails": "I was just joking, silly!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1617,
    "question": "ayudando",
    "questionDetails": "Creía que te estábamos ayudando.",
    "answer": "helping, assisting, aiding",
    "answerDetails": "We thought we were helping."
  },
  {
    "id": 1618,
    "question": "datos",
    "questionDetails": "No hay datos suficientes para reconstruir tal objeto.",
    "answer": "data",
    "answerDetails": "Insufficient data to reconstruct the requested object."
  },
  {
    "id": 1619,
    "question": "carne",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca he sido uno para negar los placeres de la carne.",
    "answer": "flesh",
    "answerDetails": "I have never been one to deny the pleasures of the flesh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1620,
    "question": "aguantar",
    "questionDetails": "Si no puede aguantar el dolor, podemos darle anestesia.",
    "answer": "endure",
    "answerDetails": "If you cannot endure the pain, we can give you an anesthetic."
  },
  {
    "id": 1621,
    "question": "cuida",
    "questionDetails": "Su padre grita a usted porque él cuida.",
    "answer": "cares, takes care, take care",
    "answerDetails": "Your father yells at you because he cares."
  },
  {
    "id": 1622,
    "question": "azul",
    "questionDetails": "Este trozo azul, es la parte letal.",
    "answer": "blue",
    "answerDetails": "This blue portion, that’s the deadly part."
  },
  {
    "id": 1623,
    "question": "inglés",
    "questionDetails": "El inglés no es un idioma fácil de aprender.",
    "answer": "english",
    "answerDetails": "English is not an easy language to learn."
  },
  {
    "id": 1624,
    "question": "ello",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca podría hablar de ello.",
    "answer": "it",
    "answerDetails": "She would never be able to talk about it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1625,
    "question": "decirlo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo sé qué fue lo que sucedió, pero temo decirlo.",
    "answer": "say it",
    "answerDetails": "I know what happened, but I am afraid to say it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1626,
    "question": "llamamos",
    "questionDetails": "Te llamamos 3 veces pero nunca contéstaste el teléfono.",
    "answer": "we called",
    "answerDetails": "We called you three times but you never answered the phone."
  },
  {
    "id": 1627,
    "question": "déjeme",
    "questionDetails": "Sea amable y déjeme echarle un vistazo.",
    "answer": "let me",
    "answerDetails": "Do me a favour, let me take a look."
  },
  {
    "id": 1628,
    "question": "mentiras",
    "questionDetails": "Diles algunas mentiras sobre mi ahora.",
    "answer": "lies",
    "answerDetails": "Tell some lies about me now."
  },
  {
    "id": 1629,
    "question": "cantar",
    "questionDetails": "La poesía debe cantar la variedad de la raza humana.",
    "answer": "sing",
    "answerDetails": "Poetry should sing the variety of the human race."
  },
  {
    "id": 1630,
    "question": "juntas",
    "questionDetails": "Juntas hemos superado la norma.",
    "answer": "together, joints, gaskets",
    "answerDetails": "Together we exceeded the norm."
  },
  {
    "id": 1631,
    "question": "olvide",
    "answer": "Forget"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632,
    "question": "ayudarte",
    "questionDetails": "Lo siento, pero no creo que pueda ayudarte con eso.",
    "answer": "help you",
    "answerDetails": "Sorry, but I don’t think I can help you with that."
  },
  {
    "id": 1633,
    "question": "ocupado",
    "questionDetails": "Ojalá tuviera más tiempo para hablar, pero estoy muy ocupado planificando la conferencia.",
    "answer": "occupied",
    "answerDetails": "I wish I had more time to talk, but I am very occupied with planning the conference."
  },
  {
    "id": 1634,
    "question": "banda",
    "questionDetails": "No encuentro la banda de frecuencia.",
    "answer": "band, belt",
    "answerDetails": "I can’t find the frequency band."
  },
  {
    "id": 1635,
    "question": "preguntando",
    "questionDetails": "Hay gente preguntando por ti.",
    "answer": "asking, wondering, inquiring",
    "answerDetails": "People are asking for you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1636,
    "question": "acompaño",
    "questionDetails": "¿Te acompaño como segundo?",
    "answer": "accompany",
    "answerDetails": "Shall I accompany as your second?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1637,
    "question": "llamé",
    "questionDetails": "Le llamé para decírselo.",
    "answer": "called, phoned, paged",
    "answerDetails": "I called to tell him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1638,
    "question": "violencia",
    "questionDetails": "La protesta irrumpió con violencia mientras llegaba la policía para controlar la multitud.",
    "answer": "violence",
    "answerDetails": "The protest erupted in violence as the police arrived to control the crowd."
  },
  {
    "id": 1639,
    "question": "fuerzas",
    "questionDetails": "Tenemos que retirar nuestras fuerzas antes del siguiente plazo.",
    "answer": "forces, strength",
    "answerDetails": "We have to withdraw our forces before the next deadline."
  },
  {
    "id": 1640,
    "question": "detalle",
    "questionDetails": "El detalle de seguridad del gobernador.",
    "answer": "detail",
    "answerDetails": "The governor’s security detail."
  },
  {
    "id": 1641,
    "question": "enseñar",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes enseñar en la televisión.",
    "answer": "teach",
    "answerDetails": "You can teach on television."
  },
  {
    "id": 1642,
    "question": "pareces",
    "questionDetails": "Te pareces a mamá.",
    "answer": "seem, look",
    "answerDetails": "You seem on mother."
  },
  {
    "id": 1643,
    "question": "limpio",
    "questionDetails": "Mira qué limpio mantienes el bar.",
    "answer": "clean",
    "answerDetails": "Look how clean you keep your bar."
  },
  {
    "id": 1644,
    "question": "hará",
    "questionDetails": "Esta es una computadora muy buena. Hará que tu trabajo sea mucho más fácil.",
    "answer": "it will make, you will make",
    "answerDetails": "This is a really nice computer. It will make your work much easier."
  },
  {
    "id": 1645,
    "question": "social",
    "questionDetails": "El domicilio social de la sociedad anónima se encuentra en Dover, Delaware.",
    "answer": "registered",
    "answerDetails": "The corporation’s registered office is in Dover, Delaware."
  },
  {
    "id": 1646,
    "question": "pecho",
    "questionDetails": "Mi madre me dijo que llevara un vestido más recatado que me cubriera el pecho.",
    "answer": "bosom",
    "answerDetails": "My mother told me to wear a more modest dress that would cover my bosoms."
  },
  {
    "id": 1647,
    "question": "juega",
    "questionDetails": "Él juega en el mismo equipo de fútbol que yo.",
    "answer": "he plays",
    "answerDetails": "He plays on the same soccer team as me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1648,
    "question": "miles",
    "questionDetails": "Hemos usado miles de ellos en estos modelos.",
    "answer": "thousands, billions",
    "answerDetails": "We use thousands of them in these models."
  },
  {
    "id": 1649,
    "question": "hacían",
    "questionDetails": "Sus cascos no hacían ruido sobre el musgo.",
    "answer": "made",
    "answerDetails": "His hooves made no sound on the moss."
  },
  {
    "id": 1650,
    "question": "méxico",
    "answer": "Mexico"
  },
  {
    "id": 1651,
    "question": "reina",
    "questionDetails": "La princesa espera convertirse algún día en reina.",
    "answer": "queen, princess",
    "answerDetails": "The princess hopes to one day become a queen."
  },
  {
    "id": 1652,
    "question": "enterar",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie se tiene que enterar.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "Nobody has to know."
  },
  {
    "id": 1653,
    "question": "servir",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca es fácil servir a 2 maestros.",
    "answer": "serve, pour",
    "answerDetails": "It is never easy to serve two masters."
  },
  {
    "id": 1654,
    "question": "vuelo",
    "questionDetails": "Está a 2 horas de vuelo desde Edimburgo.",
    "answer": "flight, flying",
    "answerDetails": "It’s two hours’ flight from Edinburgh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1655,
    "question": "personalmente",
    "questionDetails": "Nada había ido bien personalmente o políticamente.",
    "answer": "personally",
    "answerDetails": "Nothing had gone well personally or politically."
  },
  {
    "id": 1656,
    "question": "pelea",
    "questionDetails": "El paciente ingresó en el hospital con un hombro dislocado a consecuencia de una pelea.",
    "answer": "brawl, quarrel, tussle",
    "answerDetails": "The patient came into the hospital with a dislocated shoulder that he got during a brawl."
  },
  {
    "id": 1657,
    "question": "supe",
    "questionDetails": "En el momento que la vi, supe que nos traería problemas.",
    "answer": "i knew",
    "answerDetails": "The moment I saw her, I knew she would cause us trouble."
  },
  {
    "id": 1658,
    "question": "ayudarme",
    "questionDetails": "Si quieres ayudarme, mejora mi suero.",
    "answer": "help",
    "answerDetails": "You want to help, make me a better serum."
  },
  {
    "id": 1659,
    "question": "víctima",
    "questionDetails": "La víctima de un engaño.",
    "answer": "victim",
    "answerDetails": "The victim of a hoax."
  },
  {
    "id": 1660,
    "question": "tomé",
    "questionDetails": "Yo tomé esa foto.",
    "answer": "took, tome, drank",
    "answerDetails": "I took that picture."
  },
  {
    "id": 1661,
    "question": "corte",
    "questionDetails": "Vivió durante 4 años en la corte del Rey Felipe.",
    "answer": "court, cut, outage",
    "answerDetails": "He lived for four years at the court of King Philip."
  },
  {
    "id": 1662,
    "question": "respira",
    "questionDetails": "Vamos, respira para mi.",
    "answer": "breathe, breath",
    "answerDetails": "Come on, breathe for me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1663,
    "question": "motivo",
    "questionDetails": "Dame un motivo para que me quede.",
    "answer": "reason, ground, occasion",
    "answerDetails": "Give me a reason to stay."
  },
  {
    "id": 1664,
    "question": "lío",
    "questionDetails": "Rita se metió en un lío en el trabajo y tiene miedo que la despidan.",
    "answer": "jam, mess, muddle",
    "answerDetails": "Rita got herself into a bit of a jam at work and is worried she’ll lose her job."
  },
  {
    "id": 1665,
    "question": "suelta",
    "answer": "let go"
  },
  {
    "id": 1666,
    "question": "calles",
    "questionDetails": "Las calles, no la gente.",
    "answer": "streets, blocks, roads",
    "answerDetails": "The streets, not the people."
  },
  {
    "id": 1667,
    "question": "brazo",
    "questionDetails": "Apoyó los codos en los brazos de la silla.",
    "answer": "arm, boom",
    "answerDetails": "She leaned her elbows on the arms of the chair."
  },
  {
    "id": 1668,
    "question": "mostrar",
    "questionDetails": "Los músculos de sus mandíbulas mostraron blanco a través de la piel.",
    "answer": "show, display",
    "answerDetails": "The muscles of her jaws showed white through the skin."
  },
  {
    "id": 1669,
    "question": "decimos",
    "questionDetails": "Somos los caballeros que decimos.",
    "answer": "say, tenths",
    "answerDetails": "We are the knights who say."
  },
  {
    "id": 1670,
    "question": "resultado",
    "questionDetails": "Es el resultado de la votación que cuenta.",
    "answer": "outcome",
    "answerDetails": "It is the outcome of the vote that counts."
  },
  {
    "id": 1671,
    "question": "abierta",
    "questionDetails": "La pregunta abierta es con quién.",
    "answer": "open, unlocked, openly",
    "answerDetails": "The open question is with whom."
  },
  {
    "id": 1672,
    "question": "caminando",
    "questionDetails": "El paciente refiere que se lesionó la rodilla caminando.",
    "answer": "while walking, by walking",
    "answerDetails": "The patient states that she injured her knee while walking."
  },
  {
    "id": 1673,
    "question": "corto",
    "questionDetails": "Un corto tramo de pasos.",
    "answer": "short",
    "answerDetails": "A short flight of steps."
  },
  {
    "id": 1674,
    "question": "kilómetros",
    "questionDetails": "Este océano de kilómetros de agua profundas.",
    "answer": "kilometers, km, miles",
    "answerDetails": "This ocean of liquid water kilometers deep."
  },
  {
    "id": 1675,
    "question": "paciencia",
    "questionDetails": "La paciencia es clave para superar cualquier dificultad.",
    "answer": "patience, forbearance",
    "answerDetails": "Patience is key to overcoming any difficulty."
  },
  {
    "id": 1676,
    "question": "pelear",
    "answer": "feud"
  },
  {
    "id": 1677,
    "question": "contrato",
    "questionDetails": "Firmamos un contrato para comenzar con la construcción el lunes.",
    "answer": "agreement",
    "answerDetails": "We signed an agreement to begin construction on Monday."
  },
  {
    "id": 1678,
    "question": "pura",
    "questionDetails": "Pura esencia de vida.",
    "answer": "pure, sheer, purely",
    "answerDetails": "Pure essence of life."
  },
  {
    "id": 1679,
    "question": "justamente",
    "questionDetails": "Mariano se paró y expresó justamente lo que todo estábamos pensando.",
    "answer": "precisely, justly",
    "answerDetails": "Mariano stood up and expressed precisely what everybody was thinking."
  },
  {
    "id": 1680,
    "question": "estuviste",
    "questionDetails": "¿Estuviste en casa aquí todo el día o saliste?-Estuve aquí.",
    "answer": "were you",
    "answerDetails": "Were you here all day or did you go out?-I was here."
  },
  {
    "id": 1681,
    "question": "demostrar",
    "questionDetails": "Tiene que demostrar que no se encontraba allí cuando se cometió el crimen.",
    "answer": "prove, establish",
    "answerDetails": "He has to prove that he was not there at the time the crime was committed."
  },
  {
    "id": 1682,
    "question": "objetivo",
    "questionDetails": "Examine con el objetivo de alta potencia.",
    "answer": "objective, goal, aim",
    "answerDetails": "Examine with high power objective."
  },
  {
    "id": 1683,
    "question": "alegro",
    "questionDetails": "Yo también me alegro de verte.",
    "answer": "am glad, am pleased, glad",
    "answerDetails": "I too am glad to see you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1684,
    "question": "fueras",
    "questionDetails": "Fue como si fueras alguien más.",
    "answer": "were",
    "answerDetails": "It was like you were someone else."
  },
  {
    "id": 1685,
    "question": "privado",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que deberíamos discutirlo en privado.",
    "answer": "private",
    "answerDetails": "I think we should discuss this in private."
  },
  {
    "id": 1686,
    "question": "puntos",
    "questionDetails": "Pierdes tus tres puntos.",
    "answer": "points, dots, spots",
    "answerDetails": "You lose three points."
  },
  {
    "id": 1687,
    "question": "disfrutar",
    "questionDetails": "Con dinero, podríamos disfrutar de buenas comidas.",
    "answer": "enjoy",
    "answerDetails": "With money, we should enjoy good meals."
  },
  {
    "id": 1688,
    "question": "reconocer",
    "questionDetails": "El Dr. Friedman está programando su computadora para reconocer las formas de los trazos en las manos de varios escritores.",
    "answer": "recognize",
    "answerDetails": "Dr Friedman is programming his computer to recognize the shapes of strokes in the hands of various writers."
  },
  {
    "id": 1689,
    "question": "altura",
    "questionDetails": "La altura del nuevo edificio es impresionante.",
    "answer": "height",
    "answerDetails": "The height of the new building is impressive."
  },
  {
    "id": 1690,
    "question": "orgullo",
    "questionDetails": "El orgullo del pueblo es la piscina.",
    "answer": "pride",
    "answerDetails": "The pride of the village is the swimming pool."
  },
  {
    "id": 1691,
    "question": "debía",
    "questionDetails": "Dijo que le debía un favor.",
    "answer": "owed, should",
    "answerDetails": "He said you owed him one."
  },
  {
    "id": 1692,
    "question": "hablaba",
    "answer": "he talked"
  },
  {
    "id": 1693,
    "question": "doña",
    "answer": "donut"
  },
  {
    "id": 1694,
    "question": "celular",
    "questionDetails": "Tu celular pitó; se está quedando sin batería.",
    "answer": "mobile",
    "answerDetails": "Your mobile just beeped. It’s running out of juice."
  },
  {
    "id": 1695,
    "question": "niñas",
    "questionDetails": "Unas Niñas llegaron a la casa buscando a Rebecca para salir a Jugar.",
    "answer": "some girls",
    "answerDetails": "Some girls came to the house looking for Rebecca to go out and play."
  },
  {
    "id": 1696,
    "question": "pendiente",
    "questionDetails": "9 casos seguían pendientes.",
    "answer": "pending, slope, outstanding",
    "answerDetails": "9 cases were still pending."
  },
  {
    "id": 1697,
    "question": "suéltame",
    "answer": "Let me"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698,
    "question": "aceptar",
    "questionDetails": "Máquinas expendedoras que aceptaron 100 monedas de yen para latas de cerveza.",
    "answer": "accept",
    "answerDetails": "Vending machines that accepted 100-yen coins for cans of beer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1699,
    "question": "viniste",
    "questionDetails": "Bienvenido, me alegra que viniste. ¡ Entra!.",
    "answer": "you came",
    "answerDetails": "Welcome, I’m glad you came. Come on in!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1700,
    "question": "auto",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo un mapa, pero no en el auto.",
    "answer": "car",
    "answerDetails": "I have a map, but not in the car."
  },
  {
    "id": 1701,
    "question": "muero",
    "questionDetails": "Si muero al servicio de mi pueblo.",
    "answer": "die",
    "answerDetails": "To die serving my people."
  },
  {
    "id": 1702,
    "question": "irnos",
    "questionDetails": "Tenemos que irnos ahora.",
    "answer": "go, leave",
    "answerDetails": "We must go now."
  },
  {
    "id": 1703,
    "question": "podamos",
    "questionDetails": "Hasta que podamos cambiarlo.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "Just until we can change it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1704,
    "question": "siguiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Él ha estado siguiendo la porque está preocupado.",
    "answer": "following, according, tracking",
    "answerDetails": "He had me following you because he’s worried."
  },
  {
    "id": 1705,
    "question": "saberlo",
    "questionDetails": "Pensamos que usted deberia saberlo.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "We thought you should know."
  },
  {
    "id": 1706,
    "question": "buenísimo",
    "questionDetails": "Eres un actor buenísimo.",
    "answer": "terrific, great",
    "answerDetails": "You are a terrific actor."
  },
  {
    "id": 1707,
    "question": "avisar",
    "questionDetails": "La policía les avisará a las víctimas de cualquier novedad que se presente en el caso.",
    "answer": "notify, warn",
    "answerDetails": "The police will notify the victims of any new developments in the case."
  },
  {
    "id": 1708,
    "question": "tarjeta",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito su tarjeta de seguridad social.",
    "answer": "card",
    "answerDetails": "I need your card of social security."
  },
  {
    "id": 1709,
    "question": "ayudó",
    "answer": "Helped"
  },
  {
    "id": 1710,
    "question": "sociedad",
    "questionDetails": "Sociedad mercantil.",
    "answer": "company, partnership",
    "answerDetails": "Trading company."
  },
  {
    "id": 1711,
    "question": "decidí",
    "questionDetails": "Yo lo decidí, no éI.",
    "answer": "decided, resolved",
    "answerDetails": "I decided this, not him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1712,
    "question": "equivocado",
    "questionDetails": "Él alegremente admite que es el lado equivocado de 50.",
    "answer": "wrong, mistaken",
    "answerDetails": "He cheerfully admits he is the wrong side of 50."
  },
  {
    "id": 1713,
    "question": "parecen",
    "questionDetails": "Nuevas operaciones parecen posibles y útiles.",
    "answer": "seem, appear, resemble",
    "answerDetails": "Further operations would seem possible and useful."
  },
  {
    "id": 1714,
    "question": "escribir",
    "questionDetails": "Escribir a alguien.",
    "answer": "write",
    "answerDetails": "To write to somebody."
  },
  {
    "id": 1715,
    "question": "sacado",
    "questionDetails": "… de filamentos hechos punto del polypropylene sacado.",
    "answer": "extruded, pulled, get",
    "answerDetails": "… of knitted filaments of extruded polypropylene."
  },
  {
    "id": 1716,
    "question": "viejos",
    "questionDetails": "Los hilos eléctricos del exterior son viejos y frágiles.",
    "answer": "old",
    "answerDetails": "The electrical wires outside are old and fragile."
  },
  {
    "id": 1717,
    "question": "caído",
    "questionDetails": "Podrías haberte caído al agua.",
    "answer": "fallen",
    "answerDetails": "You could have fallen in the water."
  },
  {
    "id": 1718,
    "question": "camisa",
    "questionDetails": "La camisa del calentador está oxidada.",
    "answer": "jacket",
    "answerDetails": "The boiler jacket is rusted."
  },
  {
    "id": 1719,
    "question": "viven",
    "answer": "just live"
  },
  {
    "id": 1720,
    "question": "ok",
    "questionDetails": "Ok aquí va como va a funcionar.",
    "answer": "ok, okay",
    "answerDetails": "Ok so here’s how it’s going to work."
  },
  {
    "id": 1721,
    "question": "querida",
    "questionDetails": "No naciste en el sanatorio, querida.",
    "answer": "dear",
    "answerDetails": "No you weren’t born in the asylum dear."
  },
  {
    "id": 1722,
    "question": "preocupado",
    "questionDetails": "Deberías estar más preocupado por tu carácter que por tu reputación.",
    "answer": "concerned, worried, troubled",
    "answerDetails": "You should be more concerned with your character than your reputation."
  },
  {
    "id": 1723,
    "question": "programa",
    "questionDetails": "Vendedor (ORA) de programas.",
    "answer": "program",
    "answerDetails": "Program seller."
  },
  {
    "id": 1724,
    "question": "manejar",
    "questionDetails": "Losas de pavimentación pesadas pueden ser difíciles de manejar.",
    "answer": "handle, driving",
    "answerDetails": "Heavy paving slabs can be difficult to handle."
  },
  {
    "id": 1725,
    "question": "perros",
    "questionDetails": "Y perros para comer, y los gatos también.",
    "answer": "dogs, hounds",
    "answerDetails": "And dogs to eat them, and cats too."
  },
  {
    "id": 1726,
    "question": "entendí",
    "questionDetails": "Yo nunca lo entendí.",
    "answer": "understood",
    "answerDetails": "I never understood it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1727,
    "question": "quieran",
    "questionDetails": "Pueden hacer lo que quieran desde ahí arriba.",
    "answer": "want",
    "answerDetails": "They can do as they want from up there."
  },
  {
    "id": 1728,
    "question": "caballero",
    "questionDetails": "Tu hermano es muy amable; es todo un caballero.",
    "answer": "gentleman",
    "answerDetails": "Your brother is very polite; he is such a gentleman."
  },
  {
    "id": 1729,
    "question": "resultados",
    "questionDetails": "Estos resultados son sorprendentes.",
    "answer": "results, outcomes, findings",
    "answerDetails": "These are amazing results."
  },
  {
    "id": 1730,
    "question": "ataque",
    "questionDetails": "Un ataque de nervios.",
    "answer": "attack, assault",
    "answerDetails": "An attack of nerves."
  },
  {
    "id": 1731,
    "question": "sienta",
    "questionDetails": "Yo espero que usted se sienta bien pronto.",
    "answer": "feel, sit, sit down",
    "answerDetails": "I hope you feel better soon."
  },
  {
    "id": 1732,
    "question": "meto",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca me meto en estas cosas.",
    "answer": "meddle, get",
    "answerDetails": "I never meddle in these matters."
  },
  {
    "id": 1733,
    "question": "finalmente",
    "questionDetails": "Un referéndum seguido de elecciones locales, legislativas y, finalmente, presidenciales.",
    "answer": "finally, eventually",
    "answerDetails": "A referendum followed by local, legislative and, finally, presidential elections."
  },
  {
    "id": 1734,
    "question": "botella",
    "questionDetails": "Me encanta tanto la gaseosa de jengibre que me tomo una botella en 30 Segundos.",
    "answer": "bottle",
    "answerDetails": "I Love Ginger Ale so much I can drink a bottle in 30 seconds."
  },
  {
    "id": 1735,
    "question": "acabamos",
    "questionDetails": "Nosotros acabamos de encontrarlo.",
    "answer": "just, ended up",
    "answerDetails": "We just found it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1736,
    "question": "luna",
    "questionDetails": "Hace muchas lunas, yo también estuve enamorado.",
    "answer": "moon",
    "answerDetails": "Many moons ago, I too was in love."
  },
  {
    "id": 1737,
    "question": "ganado",
    "questionDetails": "Los vaqueros arrearon el ganado con la ayuda de perros pastores.",
    "answer": "herd",
    "answerDetails": "The Cowboys rounded up the herd with the help of herding dogs."
  },
  {
    "id": 1738,
    "question": "refiero",
    "questionDetails": "Me refiero a nuestro verdadero, aunque único, talento.",
    "answer": "mean, refer, talking about",
    "answerDetails": "I mean our real, if only, talent."
  },
  {
    "id": 1739,
    "question": "molestar",
    "questionDetails": "Como no quería molestar, Jay se quedó esperando fuera de su despacho.",
    "answer": "intrude",
    "answerDetails": "Not wanting to intrude, Jay SAT waiting outside her office."
  },
  {
    "id": 1740,
    "question": "ponerle",
    "questionDetails": "Es hora de ponerle un punto final a esto.",
    "answer": "put",
    "answerDetails": "It is time to put an end to this!"
  },
  {
    "id": 1741,
    "question": "poca",
    "questionDetails": "Sí, tiene muy poca.",
    "answer": "little, walking, low",
    "answerDetails": "Yes he does, but only a little."
  },
  {
    "id": 1742,
    "question": "piedra",
    "questionDetails": "Pasar las piedras del riñón puede ser bastante doloroso.",
    "answer": "stone, rock",
    "answerDetails": "Passing kidney stones can be quite painful."
  },
  {
    "id": 1743,
    "question": "hacerse",
    "questionDetails": "Ese futuro podría hacerse real.",
    "answer": "become",
    "answerDetails": "That future could become real."
  },
  {
    "id": 1744,
    "question": "roto",
    "questionDetails": "El balance se ha roto.",
    "answer": "broken",
    "answerDetails": "The balance has been broken."
  },
  {
    "id": 1745,
    "question": "presidente",
    "questionDetails": "El Presidente de la Unión Europea.",
    "answer": "president, chairman, commissioner",
    "answerDetails": "The president of the European Union."
  },
  {
    "id": 1746,
    "question": "gobierno",
    "questionDetails": "Formar gobierno.",
    "answer": "government, governing, administration",
    "answerDetails": "To form a government."
  },
  {
    "id": 1747,
    "question": "órdenes",
    "questionDetails": "Mi cometido es el de adivinar las órdenes de mi amo ya antes de que me las dé.",
    "answer": "bidding",
    "answerDetails": "It is my office to know my master’s bidding even before he asks."
  },
  {
    "id": 1748,
    "question": "luis",
    "questionDetails": "Luis no había contado con estos obstáculos.",
    "answer": "louis",
    "answerDetails": "Louis had not reckoned on these obstacles."
  },
  {
    "id": 1749,
    "question": "asesino",
    "questionDetails": "Actos asesinos de terrorismo.",
    "answer": "murderous",
    "answerDetails": "Murderous acts of terrorism."
  },
  {
    "id": 1750,
    "question": "trampa",
    "questionDetails": "El exterminador usó una trampa para atrapar los zorrillos viviendo debajo de la casa.",
    "answer": "trap, cheat, snare",
    "answerDetails": "The exterminator set a trap to catch the skunks living under the house."
  },
  {
    "id": 1751,
    "question": "pesos",
    "questionDetails": "Diez pesos a que las salta.",
    "answer": "pesos, weights, dollars",
    "answerDetails": "Ten pesos he clears ‘em all."
  },
  {
    "id": 1752,
    "question": "cuello",
    "questionDetails": "Ahí, en su cuello, claro como el agua.",
    "answer": "neck",
    "answerDetails": "There on her neck, plain as day."
  },
  {
    "id": 1753,
    "question": "nombres",
    "questionDetails": "Digo, tienes nombres.",
    "answer": "names, namespace",
    "answerDetails": "I mean, you have names."
  },
  {
    "id": 1754,
    "question": "acción",
    "questionDetails": "La acción de la película transcurría en Roma.",
    "answer": "action",
    "answerDetails": "The action of the film was set in Rome."
  },
  {
    "id": 1755,
    "question": "quedaron",
    "questionDetails": "Los laboratorios quedaron tan abandonados como nuestras esperanzas.",
    "answer": "were, stayed, remained",
    "answerDetails": "The laboratories were as abandoned as our hope."
  },
  {
    "id": 1756,
    "question": "conté",
    "questionDetails": "Le conté algo que debí haber mantenido en secreto.",
    "answer": "i told",
    "answerDetails": "I told him something that I should have kept secret."
  },
  {
    "id": 1757,
    "question": "empezando",
    "questionDetails": "La gente estaba empezando a hablar.",
    "answer": "starting, beginning, getting started",
    "answerDetails": "People were starting to talk."
  },
  {
    "id": 1758,
    "question": "arte",
    "questionDetails": "Es necesario destruir la memoria en el arte.",
    "answer": "art",
    "answerDetails": "It is necessary to destroy memory in art."
  },
  {
    "id": 1759,
    "question": "invito",
    "questionDetails": "Te invito a cenar.",
    "answer": "invite",
    "answerDetails": "I invite you to dinner."
  },
  {
    "id": 1760,
    "question": "comiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Mis amigos y yo siempre lo pasamos bien comiendo juntos.",
    "answer": "while eating",
    "answerDetails": "My friends and I always have a good time while eating together."
  },
  {
    "id": 1761,
    "question": "fuertes",
    "questionDetails": "Pero no todos sobreviven porque son fuertes.",
    "answer": "strong, forts, heavy",
    "answerDetails": "But not everything survives because it’s strong."
  },
  {
    "id": 1762,
    "question": "cerrado",
    "questionDetails": "Puso el registro ‘ cerrado ‘ en la puerta.",
    "answer": "closed",
    "answerDetails": "He put the ‘Closed’ sign up on the door."
  },
  {
    "id": 1763,
    "question": "vivimos",
    "questionDetails": "Vivimos en la Ciudad de Montevideo de 1990 a 1998.",
    "answer": "we lived, just live",
    "answerDetails": "From 1990 to 1998, we lived in the city of Montevideo."
  },
  {
    "id": 1764,
    "question": "guarda",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que el senador la guarda en el cajón superior.",
    "answer": "keeps, save, guardian",
    "answerDetails": "I believe the senator keeps it in his top drawer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1765,
    "question": "cerveza",
    "questionDetails": "La vida no es toda la cerveza y bolos.",
    "answer": "beer, lager",
    "answerDetails": "Life isn’t all beer and skittles."
  },
  {
    "id": 1766,
    "question": "estados",
    "answer": "States"
  },
  {
    "id": 1767,
    "question": "investigación",
    "questionDetails": "Las familias de las víctimas están pidiendo que se lleve a cabo una investigación oficial de las causas del descarrilamiento del tren.",
    "answer": "investigation, inquiry, study",
    "answerDetails": "The families of the victims are calling for an official investigation into what caused the train to derail."
  },
  {
    "id": 1768,
    "question": "conviene",
    "questionDetails": "El clima te conviene.",
    "answer": "agrees, suits",
    "answerDetails": "The climate agrees with you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1769,
    "question": "definitivamente",
    "questionDetails": "Definitivamente estaré en el aeropuerto para conocerte.",
    "answer": "definitely, definitively, permanently",
    "answerDetails": "I shall definitely be at the airport to meet you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1770,
    "question": "sigan",
    "questionDetails": "No se muevan y sigan mis órdenes.",
    "answer": "follow, continue",
    "answerDetails": "You will stay put and follow my orders."
  },
  {
    "id": 1771,
    "question": "huevo",
    "questionDetails": "Las ranas ponen sus huevos en el agua.",
    "answer": "egg",
    "answerDetails": "Frogs lay their eggs in water."
  },
  {
    "id": 1772,
    "question": "creas",
    "questionDetails": "Lo creas o no, trabajas para mí.",
    "answer": "believe",
    "answerDetails": "Believe it or not, you work for me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1773,
    "question": "excelente",
    "questionDetails": "“¡ Qué idea tan encantadora! ¡ Excelente!.",
    "answer": "excellent, great, fine",
    "answerDetails": "‘What a lovely idea! Excellent!’."
  },
  {
    "id": 1774,
    "question": "iglesia",
    "questionDetails": "ISOBEL entraría en la iglesia como diácono.",
    "answer": "church",
    "answerDetails": "Isobel would enter the Church as a deacon."
  },
  {
    "id": 1775,
    "question": "guste",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que te guste la carne.",
    "answer": "like, pleases",
    "answerDetails": "I hope you like steak."
  },
  {
    "id": 1776,
    "question": "dispuesto",
    "questionDetails": "Estar dispuesto (a) a hacer algo.",
    "answer": "ready, prepared, arranged",
    "answerDetails": "To be ready to do something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1777,
    "question": "proyecto",
    "questionDetails": "El departamento de Dibujo debe terminar el proyecto de postes este viernes a más tardar.",
    "answer": "design, plan",
    "answerDetails": "The drafting department has to complete the pole design by Friday at the latest."
  },
  {
    "id": 1778,
    "question": "enfrente",
    "questionDetails": "El hotel está situado justo enfrente.",
    "answer": "opposite, across",
    "answerDetails": "The hotel is situated directly opposite."
  },
  {
    "id": 1779,
    "question": "hazme",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero oír tus mejores chistes. Hazme Reír.",
    "answer": "make me",
    "answerDetails": "I want to hear your best jokes. Make me laugh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1780,
    "question": "oír",
    "questionDetails": "Odio las barras donde no puedes oírte pensar.",
    "answer": "hear",
    "answerDetails": "I hate bars where you can’t hear yourself think."
  },
  {
    "id": 1781,
    "question": "prácticamente",
    "questionDetails": "Ha mentido en prácticamente todas las ruedas de prensa.",
    "answer": "virtually, practically",
    "answerDetails": "He has lied at virtually every press conference."
  },
  {
    "id": 1782,
    "question": "despacio",
    "questionDetails": "Por favor camina despacio, mis piernas están adoloradas.",
    "answer": "slowly, softly",
    "answerDetails": "Please walk slowly, my legs are sore."
  },
  {
    "id": 1783,
    "question": "imaginar",
    "questionDetails": "Tom encuentra consuelo al imaginar un mundo mejor.",
    "answer": "imagining",
    "answerDetails": "Tom finds comfort in the imagining of a better world."
  },
  {
    "id": 1784,
    "question": "pared",
    "questionDetails": "Corredores de maratón encontraron que a menudo golpear la pared después de 17 o 18 millas.",
    "answer": "wall",
    "answerDetails": "Marathon runners found they often hit the wall after 17 or 18 miles."
  },
  {
    "id": 1785,
    "question": "pregunté",
    "questionDetails": "Le pregunté qué era tan importante para él.",
    "answer": "asked, wondered, inquired",
    "answerDetails": "I asked him what was so important for him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1786,
    "question": "importancia",
    "questionDetails": "Dar importancia a algo.",
    "answer": "importance, significance",
    "answerDetails": "To attach importance to something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1787,
    "question": "pocas",
    "questionDetails": "La obra empieza en unas pocas horas.",
    "answer": "few",
    "answerDetails": "The play starts in a few hours."
  },
  {
    "id": 1788,
    "question": "máquina",
    "questionDetails": "La nueva máquina nos ayuda a hacer el trabajo mucho más rápido.",
    "answer": "machine",
    "answerDetails": "The new machine helps us do the work much faster."
  },
  {
    "id": 1789,
    "question": "clara",
    "answer": "egg white"
  },
  {
    "id": 1790,
    "question": "coño",
    "questionDetails": "Coño se apartó de sus compañeros.",
    "answer": "pussy, cunt, cono",
    "answerDetails": "Pussy drew back from her mates."
  },
  {
    "id": 1791,
    "question": "ángel",
    "questionDetails": "Mi madre es un ángel; siempre está cuando la necesito.",
    "answer": "angel",
    "answerDetails": "My mother is an angel; she’s always there for me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1792,
    "question": "vente",
    "questionDetails": "Vente conmigo, seré lo que tu quieres que sea.",
    "answer": "come",
    "answerDetails": "I want you and the gals to come with me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1793,
    "question": "acuerda",
    "questionDetails": "Mi clienta acuerda reembolsar las deudas del demandado.",
    "answer": "agrees, remember",
    "answerDetails": "My client agrees to reimburse the defendant’s debts."
  },
  {
    "id": 1794,
    "question": "pedirte",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo que pedirte otro favor.",
    "answer": "ask",
    "answerDetails": "Have another favor to ask."
  },
  {
    "id": 1795,
    "question": "haré",
    "questionDetails": "Haré magdalenas para la fiesta de Marisol.",
    "answer": "i will make",
    "answerDetails": "I will make cupcakes for Marisol’s party."
  },
  {
    "id": 1796,
    "question": "solucionar",
    "questionDetails": "Así es como solíamos solucionar la malaria.",
    "answer": "solve",
    "answerDetails": "This is how we used to solve malaria."
  },
  {
    "id": 1797,
    "question": "borracho",
    "questionDetails": "No fue la primera vez que su esposo borracho le había pegado.",
    "answer": "drunken, stoned",
    "answerDetails": "It was not the first time her drunken husband had beaten her up."
  },
  {
    "id": 1798,
    "question": "pegar",
    "questionDetails": "Me dieron un anuncio para pegar.",
    "answer": "paste",
    "answerDetails": "I got me a notice to paste up."
  },
  {
    "id": 1799,
    "question": "rica",
    "answer": "Rica, rich, wealthy"
  },
  {
    "id": 1800,
    "question": "ridículo",
    "questionDetails": "El más ridículo es él.",
    "answer": "ridiculous",
    "answerDetails": "The most ridiculous one is him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1801,
    "question": "limpiar",
    "questionDetails": "Francis puso 3 libras en un caballo, pensando que era hora de limpiar.",
    "answer": "clean, wipe",
    "answerDetails": "Francis put three quid on a horse, figuring it was about time he cleaned up."
  },
  {
    "id": 1802,
    "question": "estilo",
    "questionDetails": "Quisiera una blusa del estilo de la que llevo.",
    "answer": "style, design",
    "answerDetails": "I would like a blouse in the style of the one I’m wearing."
  },
  {
    "id": 1803,
    "question": "maravilla",
    "questionDetails": "Es una maravilla que no te hayas herido en el choque.",
    "answer": "wonder, marvel",
    "answerDetails": "It’s a wonder that you weren’t hurt in that crash."
  },
  {
    "id": 1804,
    "question": "actuar",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que significaría, que podría actuar como una calculadora.",
    "answer": "act",
    "answerDetails": "Which would mean, it could act like a calculator."
  },
  {
    "id": 1805,
    "question": "repetir",
    "questionDetails": "El primer equipo en 19 años para repetir como campeones de la NBA.",
    "answer": "repeat, replay",
    "answerDetails": "The first team in 19 years to repeat as NBA champions."
  },
  {
    "id": 1806,
    "question": "olvidado",
    "questionDetails": "Parece que la he olvidado.",
    "answer": "forgotten",
    "answerDetails": "I seem to have forgotten it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1807,
    "question": "compré",
    "questionDetails": "Yo compré la máquina de café.",
    "answer": "bought",
    "answerDetails": "I bought the coffee machine."
  },
  {
    "id": 1808,
    "question": "terminamos",
    "questionDetails": "Recuerde aquí que terminamos con seis de ellos.",
    "answer": "ended up",
    "answerDetails": "Remember here we ended up with six of them."
  },
  {
    "id": 1809,
    "question": "pinta",
    "questionDetails": "Me compré una pinta de helado para disfrutar después de la cena.",
    "answer": "pint",
    "answerDetails": "I bought a pint of ice cream to enjoy after dinner."
  },
  {
    "id": 1810,
    "question": "orgulloso",
    "questionDetails": "Ahora eres el orgulloso dueño de una casa.",
    "answer": "proud",
    "answerDetails": "You are now the proud owner of a house."
  },
  {
    "id": 1811,
    "question": "domingo",
    "questionDetails": "El concierto se celebrará el domingo.",
    "answer": "sunday",
    "answerDetails": "The concert will be held Sunday."
  },
  {
    "id": 1812,
    "question": "dijimos",
    "questionDetails": "Mariela está enojada con nosotras porque le dijimos una mentira.",
    "answer": "we told, we said",
    "answerDetails": "Mariela is mad at us because we told her a lie."
  },
  {
    "id": 1813,
    "question": "negocios",
    "questionDetails": "Los negocios no han ido muy bien últimamente.",
    "answer": "business, deals",
    "answerDetails": "Business has been a bit off lately."
  },
  {
    "id": 1814,
    "question": "guau",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Guau! ¡ Qué fiesta!.",
    "answer": "wow, whoa",
    "answerDetails": "Wow! What a party!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1815,
    "question": "cliente",
    "questionDetails": "Hay un cliente esperando en la caja siete.",
    "answer": "customer",
    "answerDetails": "There is a customer waiting at register 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 1816,
    "question": "celebrar",
    "questionDetails": "Vamos a celebrar la junta en la sede.",
    "answer": "hold",
    "answerDetails": "We’re going to hold the meeting at the home office."
  },
  {
    "id": 1817,
    "question": "maneras",
    "questionDetails": "Puede afrontar la derrota de dos maneras.",
    "answer": "ways, manners, fashions",
    "answerDetails": "You can handle defeat in two ways."
  },
  {
    "id": 1818,
    "question": "tuviste",
    "questionDetails": "¿Tuviste suficiente comida?-Sí, gracias. Estoy lleno.",
    "answer": "did you have",
    "answerDetails": "Did you have enough food?-Yes, thank you. I’m full."
  },
  {
    "id": 1819,
    "question": "errores",
    "questionDetails": "Dije que no quería errores.",
    "answer": "errors, mistakes, bugs",
    "answerDetails": "Trinkets that did not want to errors."
  },
  {
    "id": 1820,
    "question": "premio",
    "questionDetails": "El premio de la carrera de niños fue un cono de helado.",
    "answer": "prize",
    "answerDetails": "The prize in the children’s race was an ice cream cone."
  },
  {
    "id": 1821,
    "question": "lamento",
    "questionDetails": "Su lamento sobre el ataúd de su marido desgarraba el alma.",
    "answer": "lament, wail",
    "answerDetails": "Her lament over her husband’s coffin was soul shattering."
  },
  {
    "id": 1822,
    "question": "hubieran",
    "questionDetails": "Me hubiera gustado que esos lobos te hubieran comido.",
    "answer": "had",
    "answerDetails": "I wish the wolves had eaten you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1823,
    "question": "vinieron",
    "answer": "Came"
  },
  {
    "id": 1824,
    "question": "malos",
    "answer": "bad people"
  },
  {
    "id": 1825,
    "question": "edificio",
    "questionDetails": "El edificio de las autopistas.",
    "answer": "building",
    "answerDetails": "The building of motorways."
  },
  {
    "id": 1826,
    "question": "relaciones",
    "questionDetails": "Las relaciones entre la policía y la comunidad de esta zona son buenas.",
    "answer": "relations, dealings",
    "answerDetails": "There are good relations between police and the community in this area."
  },
  {
    "id": 1827,
    "question": "animales",
    "questionDetails": "Con animales salvajes esto es muy simple.",
    "answer": "animals, pets, beasts",
    "answerDetails": "On wild animals it is very simple."
  },
  {
    "id": 1828,
    "question": "familias",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí solo viven unas pocas familias.",
    "answer": "families, households",
    "answerDetails": "Only one or two families are living here."
  },
  {
    "id": 1829,
    "question": "turno",
    "questionDetails": "Trabajador (ORA) por Turnos.",
    "answer": "shift",
    "answerDetails": "Shift worker."
  },
  {
    "id": 1830,
    "question": "míos",
    "questionDetails": "Tome uno de los míos.",
    "answer": "mine",
    "answerDetails": "Have one of mine."
  },
  {
    "id": 1831,
    "question": "educación",
    "questionDetails": "Es esencial que los padres se involucren en la educación de sus hijos.",
    "answer": "schooling, education, upbringing",
    "answerDetails": "It is essential that parents get involved in their children’s schooling."
  },
  {
    "id": 1832,
    "question": "costó",
    "questionDetails": "La vista me costó tres veces más que la casa.",
    "answer": "cost, struggled",
    "answerDetails": "That view cost me three times what the house did."
  },
  {
    "id": 1833,
    "question": "mami",
    "questionDetails": "Ahora vete con mami.",
    "answer": "mommy, mummy, mammy",
    "answerDetails": "Now veto with mommy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1834,
    "question": "papás",
    "questionDetails": "Todos tus papás te adoran.",
    "answer": "dads, parents, daddies",
    "answerDetails": "All your dads do."
  },
  {
    "id": 1835,
    "question": "agarrar",
    "questionDetails": "Los frenos agarraron muy mal.",
    "answer": "grab",
    "answerDetails": "The brakes grabbed very badly."
  },
  {
    "id": 1836,
    "question": "infierno",
    "questionDetails": "Pablo mantuvo su boca cerrada y miró Apologetic-tenemos el Infierno.",
    "answer": "hell, inferno",
    "answerDetails": "Paul kept his mouth shut and looked apologetic—we got hell."
  },
  {
    "id": 1837,
    "question": "decisiones",
    "questionDetails": "Un quarter back toma decisiones, hace elecciones.",
    "answer": "decisions, decision making, choices",
    "answerDetails": "Quarterback makes decisions, makes choices."
  },
  {
    "id": 1838,
    "question": "atender",
    "questionDetails": "Todavía puedo atender a un cliente.",
    "answer": "serve",
    "answerDetails": "I can still serve a customer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1839,
    "question": "cámaras",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitaba la casa y las cámaras.",
    "answer": "cameras, chambers, cam",
    "answerDetails": "I needed the house and the cameras."
  },
  {
    "id": 1840,
    "question": "acompañar",
    "questionDetails": "Me va a acompañar a la ciudad.",
    "answer": "accompany",
    "answerDetails": "He is to accompany me into the city."
  },
  {
    "id": 1841,
    "question": "casado",
    "questionDetails": "Para mí, es importante estar casado.",
    "answer": "married",
    "answerDetails": "It means something to me to be married."
  },
  {
    "id": 1842,
    "question": "gustar",
    "questionDetails": "Te dije que le iba a gustar.",
    "answer": "like",
    "answerDetails": "Told you she’d like it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1843,
    "question": "razones",
    "answer": "rationale"
  },
  {
    "id": 1844,
    "question": "aparecer",
    "questionDetails": "Al amanecer, el sol aparecerá por encima de las montañas.",
    "answer": "appear",
    "answerDetails": "At sunrise, the sun will appear above the mountains."
  },
  {
    "id": 1845,
    "question": "desayuno",
    "questionDetails": "Quizas podamos tomar desayuno.",
    "answer": "breakfast",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe we can grab breakfast."
  },
  {
    "id": 1846,
    "question": "mentir",
    "questionDetails": "Porque no tiene motivos para mentir.",
    "answer": "lie",
    "answerDetails": "He has no reason to lie."
  },
  {
    "id": 1847,
    "question": "maestro",
    "questionDetails": "No eres tu propio maestro.",
    "answer": "master",
    "answerDetails": "You are not your own master."
  },
  {
    "id": 1848,
    "question": "hubiese",
    "questionDetails": "Si hubiese ajustado los frenos.",
    "answer": "had",
    "answerDetails": "I had the brakes all fixed."
  },
  {
    "id": 1849,
    "question": "fueran",
    "questionDetails": "Como si las palabras fueran sonidos y materia.",
    "answer": "were",
    "answerDetails": "Talk as if words were sounds and matter."
  },
  {
    "id": 1850,
    "question": "conseguido",
    "questionDetails": "Me dijiste que habías conseguido un departamento.",
    "answer": "got, managed, achieved",
    "answerDetails": "You told me you got an apartment."
  },
  {
    "id": 1851,
    "question": "dientes",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que importa son los dientes.",
    "answer": "teeth",
    "answerDetails": "The teeth are more important."
  },
  {
    "id": 1852,
    "question": "hecha",
    "questionDetails": "Usaba ropa hecha de bolsas.",
    "answer": "made, done",
    "answerDetails": "She wore dresses made of feed sacks."
  },
  {
    "id": 1853,
    "question": "pensamos",
    "questionDetails": "Sí, pensamos que habías ido al centro o algo.",
    "answer": "thought, figured",
    "answerDetails": "I thought you went downtown or something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1854,
    "question": "aprendí",
    "questionDetails": "Yo aprendí de esto.",
    "answer": "learned",
    "answerDetails": "I learned something from it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1855,
    "question": "acto",
    "questionDetails": "Muchas de las obras de Shakespeare se dividen en 5 actos.",
    "answer": "act, deed",
    "answerDetails": "Many Shakespeare plays are divided into five acts."
  },
  {
    "id": 1856,
    "question": "trabajaba",
    "questionDetails": "Trabajaba en el aeropuerto durante años.",
    "answer": "he worked",
    "answerDetails": "He worked at the airport for years."
  },
  {
    "id": 1857,
    "question": "serán",
    "answer": "will you be"
  },
  {
    "id": 1858,
    "question": "vacío",
    "questionDetails": "Ver el enorme vacío del espacio era psicológicamente más difícil de lo que había esperado el astronauta.",
    "answer": "emptiness, gap, vacuum",
    "answerDetails": "Seeing the vast emptiness of space was psychologically more difficult than the astronaut had expected."
  },
  {
    "id": 1859,
    "question": "m",
    "questionDetails": "La fila m se vería así.",
    "answer": "m, metres, meters",
    "answerDetails": "The m row would look like this."
  },
  {
    "id": 1860,
    "question": "cálmate",
    "questionDetails": "Cálmate. El tipo no te quería insultar.",
    "answer": "calm yourself",
    "answerDetails": "Calm yourself. The guy wasn’t trying to insult you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1861,
    "question": "inocente",
    "questionDetails": "Aunque lo hallaron con sangre en las manos, jura ser inocente.",
    "answer": "innocent",
    "answerDetails": "Even though he was found with blood on his hands, he swears he’s innocent."
  },
  {
    "id": 1862,
    "question": "universidad",
    "questionDetails": "Solo una mínima parte de los estudiantes pueden pagar la universidad.",
    "answer": "university, college, school",
    "answerDetails": "Only a fraction of students can pay for university."
  },
  {
    "id": 1863,
    "question": "contestar",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo tenías que contestar el teléfono.",
    "answer": "answer",
    "answerDetails": "All you have to do is answer the phone."
  },
  {
    "id": 1864,
    "question": "defender",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos poniendo todo nuestro esfuerzo en defender esta causa.",
    "answer": "champion",
    "answerDetails": "We’re putting all our efforts into championing this cause."
  },
  {
    "id": 1865,
    "question": "lucha",
    "questionDetails": "La lucha contra el cáncer.",
    "answer": "fight, struggle",
    "answerDetails": "The fight against cancer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1866,
    "question": "estudio",
    "questionDetails": "Nuestro estudio incluyó muchas profesiones y actividades diferentes.",
    "answer": "survey, firm",
    "answerDetails": "Our survey looked at many different professions and activities."
  },
  {
    "id": 1867,
    "question": "consecuencias",
    "questionDetails": "Parte de las consecuencias tras el tiroteo fue el cambio en la política de armas.",
    "answer": "aftermath",
    "answerDetails": "A change in the gun policy was a part of the aftermath after the shooting."
  },
  {
    "id": 1868,
    "question": "entrega",
    "questionDetails": "Las novelas de Dickens se publicaron primero por entregas en revistas semanales o mensuales.",
    "answer": "installment, shipment",
    "answerDetails": "Dickens’ novels were first published in installments in weekly or monthly magazines."
  },
  {
    "id": 1869,
    "question": "pasen",
    "questionDetails": "Sean amables y pasen esto.",
    "answer": "pass, spend",
    "answerDetails": "Be good and pass this."
  },
  {
    "id": 1870,
    "question": "enferma",
    "answer": "Sick"
  },
  {
    "id": 1871,
    "question": "voluntad",
    "questionDetails": "No sé si tengo la voluntad para terminar este proyecto.",
    "answer": "willpower, wish, volition",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t know if I have the willpower to finish this project."
  },
  {
    "id": 1872,
    "question": "tomamos",
    "questionDetails": "Tomamos sándwiches al parque para hacer un picnic.",
    "answer": "we took, we drank",
    "answerDetails": "We took sandwiches to the park to have a picnic."
  },
  {
    "id": 1873,
    "question": "vuelves",
    "questionDetails": "Si me las vuelves a pedir, son tuyas.",
    "answer": "again",
    "answerDetails": "Ask me again and it’s yours."
  },
  {
    "id": 1874,
    "question": "elegir",
    "questionDetails": "Hay muchas versiones para elegir.",
    "answer": "choose, select, pick",
    "answerDetails": "There are many versions to choose from."
  },
  {
    "id": 1875,
    "question": "vecinos",
    "answer": "townspeople"
  },
  {
    "id": 1876,
    "question": "pesado",
    "questionDetails": "El tipo de arriba era demasiado pesado.",
    "answer": "heavy",
    "answerDetails": "Top guy was just too heavy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1877,
    "question": "recuerdas",
    "questionDetails": "¿Recuerdas cuando éramos amigos?",
    "answer": "do you remember",
    "answerDetails": "Do you remember when we used to be friends?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1878,
    "question": "llevando",
    "questionDetails": "Ese palomo astuto está llevando mensajes a los barcos.",
    "answer": "carrying, taking, leading",
    "answerDetails": "That sneaky pigeon’s been carrying messages to ships."
  },
  {
    "id": 1879,
    "question": "habido",
    "questionDetails": "Habrá habido alguien que hayas querido ser.",
    "answer": "been",
    "answerDetails": "There must have been someone you wanted to be."
  },
  {
    "id": 1880,
    "question": "natural",
    "questionDetails": "Tomamos el curso natural.",
    "answer": "natural, nature, naturally",
    "answerDetails": "We took the natural course."
  },
  {
    "id": 1881,
    "question": "deberían",
    "questionDetails": "Deberían sentarse y no hacer nada.",
    "answer": "should",
    "answerDetails": "You should sit around and do nothing."
  },
  {
    "id": 1882,
    "question": "estando",
    "answer": "by being"
  },
  {
    "id": 1883,
    "question": "revés",
    "questionDetails": "El partido sufrió un serio revés en las recientes elecciones.",
    "answer": "setback",
    "answerDetails": "The party suffered a major setback in the recent elections."
  },
  {
    "id": 1884,
    "question": "historias",
    "questionDetails": "Pero ninguna de estas historias era verdad.",
    "answer": "stories, histories, tales",
    "answerDetails": "But none of these stories were true."
  },
  {
    "id": 1885,
    "question": "treinta",
    "questionDetails": "Treinta mil o nada.",
    "answer": "thirty",
    "answerDetails": "Thirty thousand or nothing."
  },
  {
    "id": 1886,
    "question": "aguanta",
    "questionDetails": "No se desespera, sino que calla y aguanta.",
    "answer": "enduring, hold",
    "answerDetails": "Never despairing, but enduring it silently."
  },
  {
    "id": 1887,
    "question": "metiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Te estabas metiendo en nuestras mentes.",
    "answer": "messing, tucking, poking",
    "answerDetails": "You were messing with our heads."
  },
  {
    "id": 1888,
    "question": "tipos",
    "questionDetails": "Acá tenemos de dos tipos diferentes.",
    "answer": "types, kinds, guys",
    "answerDetails": "Here we have two different types."
  },
  {
    "id": 1889,
    "question": "crea",
    "answer": "it creates"
  },
  {
    "id": 1890,
    "question": "máximo",
    "questionDetails": "Las ventas de taquilla alcanzaron un nuevo máximo con el estreno de la película.",
    "answer": "high, ultimate, upper",
    "answerDetails": "Box office sales reached a new high with the opening of the movie."
  },
  {
    "id": 1891,
    "question": "energía",
    "questionDetails": "Esos niños siempre están llenos de energía.",
    "answer": "energy",
    "answerDetails": "Those kids are always full of energy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1892,
    "question": "pediste",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí tienes el periódico y un café, como pediste.",
    "answer": "you asked",
    "answerDetails": "Here is the newspaper and a coffee, just like you asked."
  },
  {
    "id": 1893,
    "question": "copa",
    "questionDetails": "Jugar en la Copa es lo mejor que nunca.",
    "answer": "cup, drink, goblet",
    "answerDetails": "Playing in the Cup is the best thing ever."
  },
  {
    "id": 1894,
    "question": "casos",
    "questionDetails": "En mi trabajo, hay casos muy diferentes.",
    "answer": "cases, instances, situations",
    "answerDetails": "In my business, you got many kind of cases."
  },
  {
    "id": 1895,
    "question": "trajiste",
    "questionDetails": "Trajiste las bebidas, ¿verdad?",
    "answer": "you brought",
    "answerDetails": "You brought the drinks, right?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1896,
    "question": "dimos",
    "answer": "Gave"
  },
  {
    "id": 1897,
    "question": "muestra",
    "questionDetails": "Me encanta comprar en ese supermercado; siempre te dan a probar muestras de nuevos productos.",
    "answer": "sample, example, showing",
    "answerDetails": "I love shopping at that grocery store; they always let you taste samples of new products."
  },
  {
    "id": 1898,
    "question": "nació",
    "questionDetails": "Le compré el elefante el día que nació.",
    "answer": "was born, born",
    "answerDetails": "I bought the elephant for him the day he was born."
  },
  {
    "id": 1899,
    "question": "buscan",
    "questionDetails": "Algunos sufren y buscan la salvación.",
    "answer": "seek, looking, searching",
    "answerDetails": "Others suffer and seek salvation."
  },
  {
    "id": 1900,
    "question": "quedaba",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo entonces se quedaba.",
    "answer": "remained, stayed, was",
    "answerDetails": "Then only she remained."
  },
  {
    "id": 1901,
    "question": "esposo",
    "questionDetails": "Conocí a mi esposo en julio de 1972.",
    "answer": "husband",
    "answerDetails": "I met my husband in July of 1972."
  },
  {
    "id": 1902,
    "question": "dólares",
    "questionDetails": "Enviamos millones de dólares.",
    "answer": "dollars, bucks, USD",
    "answerDetails": "We sent millions of dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 1903,
    "question": "preocupada",
    "questionDetails": "Parece preocupada y cansada.",
    "answer": "worried, concerned, preoccupied",
    "answerDetails": "She looks worried and tired."
  },
  {
    "id": 1904,
    "question": "ex",
    "questionDetails": "Ella y su exmarido siguen siendo buenos amigos.",
    "answer": "former",
    "answerDetails": "She remains good friends with her former husband."
  },
  {
    "id": 1905,
    "question": "termine",
    "answer": "Finish"
  },
  {
    "id": 1906,
    "question": "pudiste",
    "questionDetails": "¿Pudiste haber dejado tu bolsa en la fiesta?",
    "answer": "could you",
    "answerDetails": "Could you have left your purse at the party?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1907,
    "question": "tengamos",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie de que tengamos que preocuparnos.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "Nobody you have to worry about."
  },
  {
    "id": 1908,
    "question": "firmar",
    "questionDetails": "Así usted y su experto pueden firmar estos.",
    "answer": "sign",
    "answerDetails": "So you and your expert can sign these."
  },
  {
    "id": 1909,
    "question": "clave",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito la clave para el crucigrama del New York Times.",
    "answer": "key, password",
    "answerDetails": "I need the key to the New York Times crossword puzzle."
  },
  {
    "id": 1910,
    "question": "respecto",
    "questionDetails": "En este respecto, creo que cada país tiene que asumir la responsabilidad por un futuro sostenible.",
    "answer": "regard, with respect to",
    "answerDetails": "In that regard, I think each country must assume responsibility for a sustainable future."
  },
  {
    "id": 1911,
    "question": "chiste",
    "questionDetails": "Steven contó muchos chistes en la fiesta para hacernos reír.",
    "answer": "joke, prank",
    "answerDetails": "Steven told a lot of jokes at the party to make us laugh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1912,
    "question": "bolsa",
    "questionDetails": "Llegar temprano a la bolsa de un asiento en la primera fila.",
    "answer": "bag, stock exchange, pouch",
    "answerDetails": "Get there early to bag a seat in the front row."
  },
  {
    "id": 1913,
    "question": "mensajes",
    "questionDetails": "No hay más mensajes claros en este mundo.",
    "answer": "messages, posts, emails",
    "answerDetails": "There are no more clear messages in this world."
  },
  {
    "id": 1914,
    "question": "podrá",
    "questionDetails": "Así tendrás un cuerpo del que nadie podrá decir nada.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "Get a body that no one can say anything about."
  },
  {
    "id": 1915,
    "question": "consigo",
    "questionDetails": "Marina se llevó a los niños consigo.",
    "answer": "with her",
    "answerDetails": "Marina took the kids with her."
  },
  {
    "id": 1916,
    "question": "salieron",
    "answer": "Left"
  },
  {
    "id": 1917,
    "question": "sobra",
    "questionDetails": "La sobra de maíz hizo que bajara el precio del cereal.",
    "answer": "surplus",
    "answerDetails": "The surplus of corn brought the price of cereal down."
  },
  {
    "id": 1918,
    "question": "pasas",
    "questionDetails": "Ahora es tiempo de agregar las pasas.",
    "answer": "raisins, spend, currants",
    "answerDetails": "Now it’s time to add the raisins."
  },
  {
    "id": 1919,
    "question": "igualmente",
    "questionDetails": "La discusión de seguimiento es igualmente importante.",
    "answer": "equally, similarly, likewise",
    "answerDetails": "Follow-up discussion is equally as important."
  },
  {
    "id": 1920,
    "question": "decidir",
    "questionDetails": "Decidir hacer algo.",
    "answer": "decide",
    "answerDetails": "To decide to do something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1921,
    "question": "quedarte",
    "questionDetails": "De veras no tienes que quedarte.",
    "answer": "stay, stick around",
    "answerDetails": "You really don’t have to stay."
  },
  {
    "id": 1922,
    "question": "sonrisa",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Deja de mirarme con esa sonrisa tonta y contesta a la pregunta!.",
    "answer": "grin",
    "answerDetails": "Quit looking at me with that foolish grin and answer the question!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1923,
    "question": "caras",
    "questionDetails": "Las dos caras y las cabezas están perfectamente enfocadas.",
    "answer": "faces, expensive, sides",
    "answerDetails": "Both the faces and headlines are in perfect focus."
  },
  {
    "id": 1924,
    "question": "sabíamos",
    "questionDetails": "Ni siquiera nosotros sabíamos.",
    "answer": "knew",
    "answerDetails": "None of us knew."
  },
  {
    "id": 1925,
    "question": "buscamos",
    "questionDetails": "Buscamos en el sótano pero no encontramos nada.",
    "answer": "we looked",
    "answerDetails": "We looked in the basement but we didn’t find anything."
  },
  {
    "id": 1926,
    "question": "decían",
    "questionDetails": "Como decían cuando interrumpiste, la tienda ya cerró.",
    "answer": "they were saying, they would say",
    "answerDetails": "As they were saying when you interrupted, the store has already closed."
  },
  {
    "id": 1927,
    "question": "mmm",
    "questionDetails": "Mmm deberías tener algo.",
    "answer": "mmm, um, hmm",
    "answerDetails": "Mmm you should have some."
  },
  {
    "id": 1928,
    "question": "casar",
    "questionDetails": "Y te vuelves a casar una semana después del divorcio.",
    "answer": "marry, get married",
    "answerDetails": "And you get to marry one weeks after divorce."
  },
  {
    "id": 1929,
    "question": "amistad",
    "questionDetails": "La amistad y el amor son lo más importante en la vida.",
    "answer": "friendship, friendliness",
    "answerDetails": "Friendship and love are the most important things in life."
  },
  {
    "id": 1930,
    "question": "talento",
    "questionDetails": "Me refiero a nuestro verdadero, aunque único, talento.",
    "answer": "talent",
    "answerDetails": "I mean our real, if only, talent."
  },
  {
    "id": 1931,
    "question": "decirles",
    "questionDetails": "Mis padres vendrán mañana. No puedo esperar a decirles de mi trabajo nuevo.",
    "answer": "tell them",
    "answerDetails": "My parents are coming over tomorrow. I can’t wait to tell them about my new job."
  },
  {
    "id": 1932,
    "question": "firme",
    "questionDetails": "Durante el terremoto, la torre se mantuvo firme.",
    "answer": "steady, steadfast, solid",
    "answerDetails": "The tower remained steady during the earthquake."
  },
  {
    "id": 1933,
    "question": "mintiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Ellos están mintiendo contra las doctrinas.",
    "answer": "lying, Iying, lyin’",
    "answerDetails": "They are lying against the doctrines."
  },
  {
    "id": 1934,
    "question": "vernos",
    "questionDetails": "Pero podríamos no volver a vernos por un buen rato.",
    "answer": "seeing each other, meet, hang out",
    "answerDetails": "But we might not be seeing each other for a while."
  },
  {
    "id": 1935,
    "question": "delito",
    "questionDetails": "Cometer un delito, delinquir.",
    "answer": "crime, offence, offense",
    "answerDetails": "To commit a crime."
  },
  {
    "id": 1936,
    "question": "quítate",
    "questionDetails": "Quítate la ropa ahora mismo.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "Take all your clothes off right now."
  },
  {
    "id": 1937,
    "question": "sacaste",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que ya me sacaste todo el veneno.",
    "answer": "got",
    "answerDetails": "I think you got all the venom out."
  },
  {
    "id": 1938,
    "question": "metí",
    "questionDetails": "Me metí justo en el medio del lío.",
    "answer": "got, shoved",
    "answerDetails": "I got right on top of that mess."
  },
  {
    "id": 1939,
    "question": "estaré",
    "questionDetails": "Yo estaré muy honrado.",
    "answer": "be",
    "answerDetails": "I would be very honoured."
  },
  {
    "id": 1940,
    "question": "muevas",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito que no muevas tu cuello.",
    "answer": "move",
    "answerDetails": "I need you to not move your neck."
  },
  {
    "id": 1941,
    "question": "ilusión",
    "questionDetails": "¿Fue magia de veras o simplemente una ilusión?",
    "answer": "illusion",
    "answerDetails": "Was that really magic or just an illusion?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1942,
    "question": "pega",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre habrá pegas; se trata de cómo lidies con ellas.",
    "answer": "snag",
    "answerDetails": "There will always be snags; it’s just about how you deal with them."
  },
  {
    "id": 1943,
    "question": "famoso",
    "questionDetails": "El país es famoso por su belleza natural.",
    "answer": "famous, renowned",
    "answerDetails": "The country is famous for its natural beauty."
  },
  {
    "id": 1944,
    "question": "recuerdos",
    "questionDetails": "Colecciona portadas de álbumes, fotos y otros recuerdos de los Beatles.",
    "answer": "memorabilia, associations",
    "answerDetails": "She collects Beatles album covers, photos, and other memorabilia."
  },
  {
    "id": 1945,
    "question": "libres",
    "questionDetails": "Los chicos tienen que ser libres en la escuela.",
    "answer": "free",
    "answerDetails": "Children must be free at school."
  },
  {
    "id": 1946,
    "question": "robo",
    "questionDetails": "Brandon fue detenido por robo de autos.",
    "answer": "theft, robbery, steal",
    "answerDetails": "Brandon was arrested for auto theft."
  },
  {
    "id": 1947,
    "question": "parezca",
    "questionDetails": "Y eso hace que parezca como si fuera verdad.",
    "answer": "seem, look, oddly enough",
    "answerDetails": "And that makes it seem as if it were true."
  },
  {
    "id": 1948,
    "question": "haberlo",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie podía haberlo planeado.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "Nobody could have planned this."
  },
  {
    "id": 1949,
    "question": "tirado",
    "questionDetails": "Si encuentro tus juguetes tirados en el suelo, ¡ los boto a la basura!.",
    "answer": "lying",
    "answerDetails": "If I find your toys lying on the floor, I’ll put them in the trash!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1950,
    "question": "levanta",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando levanta la mano a la cabeza.",
    "answer": "raises, rises, lift",
    "answerDetails": "When it raises hand at the top."
  },
  {
    "id": 1951,
    "question": "mires",
    "questionDetails": "A menos que mires por aquí.",
    "answer": "look, stare at, stare",
    "answerDetails": "Except if you look over here."
  },
  {
    "id": 1952,
    "question": "vuelven",
    "questionDetails": "Estas cosas vuelven y vuelven.",
    "answer": "return, come back",
    "answerDetails": "These things do return."
  },
  {
    "id": 1953,
    "question": "lunes",
    "questionDetails": "Te llamaré el lunes.",
    "answer": "monday",
    "answerDetails": "I’ll ring you Monday."
  },
  {
    "id": 1954,
    "question": "cuente",
    "questionDetails": "Haz que el sacrificio cuente para algo.",
    "answer": "count",
    "answerDetails": "Make the sacrifice count for something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1955,
    "question": "belleza",
    "questionDetails": "Es una verdadera Belleza.",
    "answer": "beauty",
    "answerDetails": "She really is a beauty."
  },
  {
    "id": 1956,
    "question": "ambulancia",
    "questionDetails": "Puedo llamar un taxi o una ambulancia.",
    "answer": "ambulance",
    "answerDetails": "I could call you a cab or an ambulance."
  },
  {
    "id": 1957,
    "question": "norte",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes ver si estás caminado hacia el norte usando el sol y un reloj.",
    "answer": "north",
    "answerDetails": "You can see if you’re walking to the north by using the sun and a watch."
  },
  {
    "id": 1958,
    "question": "pusiste",
    "questionDetails": "Pusiste salvia en los sandwich es?",
    "answer": "put",
    "answerDetails": "Put sage in the sandwiches?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1959,
    "question": "volar",
    "questionDetails": "Guy Fawkes urdió un complot para volar el Parlamento británico el 5 de noviembre de 1605.",
    "answer": "blast",
    "answerDetails": "Guy Fawkes plotted to blast the Houses of Parliament on November 5th, 1605."
  },
  {
    "id": 1960,
    "question": "interés",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que está perdiendo interés en mí.",
    "answer": "interest",
    "answerDetails": "I think he’s losing interest in me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1961,
    "question": "fría",
    "questionDetails": "La sopa está fría.",
    "answer": "cold, cool, chilly",
    "answerDetails": "The soup is cold."
  },
  {
    "id": 1962,
    "question": "golpes",
    "questionDetails": "El equipo de rescate escuchaba golpes de dentro del edificio derrumbado.",
    "answer": "knocking",
    "answerDetails": "Rescuers could hear a knocking coming from the collapsed building."
  },
  {
    "id": 1963,
    "question": "enfermedad",
    "questionDetails": "La violencia es una enfermedad social y debe ser tratada como tal.",
    "answer": "disease, illness, sickness",
    "answerDetails": "Violence is a social disease and it should be treated as such."
  },
  {
    "id": 1964,
    "question": "propósito",
    "questionDetails": "El propósito de Kim es de ser la mejor gimnasta en su estado.",
    "answer": "aim, purpose",
    "answerDetails": "Kim’s aim is to be the best gymnast in her state."
  },
  {
    "id": 1965,
    "question": "ponerme",
    "questionDetails": "No tengo nada lindo para ponerme.",
    "answer": "wear, get",
    "answerDetails": "I have nothing nice to wear."
  },
  {
    "id": 1966,
    "question": "llegas",
    "questionDetails": "Pero una vez que llegas a ello.",
    "answer": "arrive, get",
    "answerDetails": "But once you arrive to it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1967,
    "question": "tendremos",
    "questionDetails": "Si regresas mañana, tendremos un nuevo cargamento de este zapato.",
    "answer": "we will have, we will get",
    "answerDetails": "If you come back tomorrow, we will have a new shipment of this shoe."
  },
  {
    "id": 1968,
    "question": "quedando",
    "questionDetails": "Mi familia se está quedando en casa.",
    "answer": "staying",
    "answerDetails": "My family’s staying at my place."
  },
  {
    "id": 1969,
    "question": "emoción",
    "questionDetails": "Su voz estaba llena de emoción mientras recordaba la vida de su abuela.",
    "answer": "emotion, thrill",
    "answerDetails": "Her voice was full of emotion as she remembered her grandmother’s life."
  },
  {
    "id": 1970,
    "question": "mandado",
    "questionDetails": "¿Tienes que hacer algún mandado?-Sí, tengo que ir al correo, al banco y a la farmacia.",
    "answer": "errand",
    "answerDetails": "Do you have any errands to do?-Yes, I need to go to the post office, the bank, and the pharmacy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1971,
    "question": "enseñó",
    "questionDetails": "Estoy agradecido con Jim. Me enseñó una valiosa lección.",
    "answer": "he taught, he showed",
    "answerDetails": "I am grateful to Jim. He taught me a valuable lesson."
  },
  {
    "id": 1972,
    "question": "escuchas",
    "questionDetails": "Tú lo escuchas, pero no te giras.",
    "answer": "hear, listen, listeners",
    "answerDetails": "You hear him, but you don’t turn around."
  },
  {
    "id": 1973,
    "question": "podíamos",
    "answer": "could"
  },
  {
    "id": 1974,
    "question": "reír",
    "questionDetails": "Sus chistes siempre me hacen reír.",
    "answer": "laugh",
    "answerDetails": "His jokes always make me laugh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1975,
    "question": "cola",
    "questionDetails": "Tu perro mueve la cola porque está contento.",
    "answer": "tail",
    "answerDetails": "Your dog wags his tail because he’s happy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1976,
    "question": "empiezo",
    "questionDetails": "El empiezo de esa canción me da risa.",
    "answer": "beginning",
    "answerDetails": "The beginning of that song makes me laugh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1977,
    "question": "formar",
    "answer": "make up"
  },
  {
    "id": 1978,
    "question": "salía",
    "questionDetails": "Había una mano que salía de la computadora.",
    "answer": "out",
    "answerDetails": "There was a hand coming out of the computer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1979,
    "question": "carro",
    "questionDetails": "Enganchó los caballos al carro.",
    "answer": "cart, carriage, wheels",
    "answerDetails": "He hitched the horses up to the cart."
  },
  {
    "id": 1980,
    "question": "droga",
    "questionDetails": "Drogarse, tomar drogas.",
    "answer": "drug, dope",
    "answerDetails": "To take drugs."
  },
  {
    "id": 1981,
    "question": "nena",
    "questionDetails": "¿Nena, estás bien? Te ves triste.",
    "answer": "baby",
    "answerDetails": "Are you okay, baby? You look sad."
  },
  {
    "id": 1982,
    "question": "averiguar",
    "questionDetails": "Debo averiguar esto para mi investigación.",
    "answer": "ascertain",
    "answerDetails": "I must ascertain this for my investigation."
  },
  {
    "id": 1983,
    "question": "piense",
    "questionDetails": "Piense en qué diría si estuviera viva.",
    "answer": "think, consider",
    "answerDetails": "Think what she would say if she were alive."
  },
  {
    "id": 1984,
    "question": "llamadas",
    "questionDetails": "Que hagan sus propias llamadas.",
    "answer": "calls, phone calls",
    "answerDetails": "Have them make their own calls."
  },
  {
    "id": 1985,
    "question": "medios",
    "questionDetails": "Cada país en el mundo tiene los medios para hacer etanol.",
    "answer": "means",
    "answerDetails": "Every country in the world has the means to make ethanol."
  },
  {
    "id": 1986,
    "question": "documentos",
    "questionDetails": "El cumplimiento de los documentos contables.",
    "answer": "documents, papers, records",
    "answerDetails": "The completion of accounting documents."
  },
  {
    "id": 1987,
    "question": "revisar",
    "questionDetails": "El médico me ha aumentado la dosis y va a revisar la situación dentro de 6 meses.",
    "answer": "review, check, revise",
    "answerDetails": "The doctor increased my dose and is going to review the situation in 6 months’ time."
  },
  {
    "id": 1988,
    "question": "estrella",
    "questionDetails": "Su destino de golf fue escrito en las estrellas.",
    "answer": "star",
    "answerDetails": "His golf destiny was written in the stars."
  },
  {
    "id": 1989,
    "question": "invitar",
    "questionDetails": "Le tuve que invitar.",
    "answer": "invite",
    "answerDetails": "I had to invite him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1990,
    "question": "hazlo",
    "questionDetails": "Me da miedo echarme un clavado a la piscina.-¡ Hazlo ya!.",
    "answer": "do it",
    "answerDetails": "I’m afraid to dive into the pool.-Do it already!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1991,
    "question": "espectacular",
    "questionDetails": "El capitán de la Selección Inglesa anotó un gol espectacular en los momentos finales del partido.",
    "answer": "spectacular, dramatic",
    "answerDetails": "The England captain scored a spectacular goal in the final moments of the game."
  },
  {
    "id": 1992,
    "question": "venta",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Rompimos el récord hoy con 150 ventas en total!.",
    "answer": "sale, selling",
    "answerDetails": "We broke the record today at 150 total sales!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1993,
    "question": "sur",
    "questionDetails": "Dakota del Sur.",
    "answer": "south",
    "answerDetails": "South Dakota."
  },
  {
    "id": 1994,
    "question": "material",
    "questionDetails": "¿Han traído todo el material para hacer el trabajo?",
    "answer": "equipment",
    "answerDetails": "Have you brought all the equipment to do the job?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1995,
    "question": "preparando",
    "questionDetails": "Me pasé semanas preparando esa expedición.",
    "answer": "preparing, getting ready, prepping",
    "answerDetails": "I spent weeks preparing that expedition."
  },
  {
    "id": 1996,
    "question": "vivido",
    "answer": "vivid"
  },
  {
    "id": 1997,
    "question": "funcionar",
    "questionDetails": "Funcionarios contratados que trabajan con las deudas de sus padres.",
    "answer": "work",
    "answerDetails": "Indentured servants working off their parents’ debts."
  },
  {
    "id": 1998,
    "question": "dulce",
    "questionDetails": "Compré unos dulces para los niños.",
    "answer": "sweet, fresh, sugar",
    "answerDetails": "I bought some sweets for the kids."
  },
  {
    "id": 1999,
    "question": "distancia",
    "questionDetails": "Educación a distancia.",
    "answer": "distance",
    "answerDetails": "Distance learning."
  },
  {
    "id": 2000,
    "question": "veinte",
    "questionDetails": "Estuvieron aquí hace menos de veinte minutos.",
    "answer": "twenty",
    "answerDetails": "They were here less than twenty minutes ago."
  }
]
